<dashboard version="1.1">
  <label>TA-Netflow Setup</label>
  <row>
    <html>
    <p>
        Welcome to the Technology Add-On for NetFlow!
    </p>
    <br></br>
    <p>
        <b>IMPORTANT:</b> This technology add-on collects Flow data processed by NetFlow Optimizer™ (NFO) software by NetFlow Logic, providing Splunk CIM compliant field names, eventtypes and tags for *flow data. It could be deployed in your Splunk Enterprise or Splunk Cloud environments.
    </p>
    <p>
      NFO supports NetFlow v5, v9, sFlow, J-Flow, IPFIX, Cisco ASA NSEL, Cisco HSL, Cisco AVC, Palo Alto Networks NetFlow, Amazon VPC Flow Logs, Google VPC Flow Logs, Microsoft Azure NSG Flow Logs, etc.
    </p>
    <p>
        <ul>
            <li>
                Visit <a target="_blank" href="https://www.netflowlogic.com/download/">https://www.netflowlogic.com/download/</a> to download NFO software.
            </li>
            <li>
                Request a free 60 day NetFlow Optimizer trial license by completing the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.netflowlogic.com/register-form/">simple registration form</a>
            </li>
            <li>
                Configure NetFlow Optimizer input to receive NetFlow/sFlow/IPFIX, and output to send NFO syslogs to your Splunk system.
            </li>
        </ul>
    </p>
    <h3>TECHNOLOGY ADD-ON FOR NETFLOW APPLICATION CONFIGURATION</h3>
    <p>
      This technology add-on should be installed on your Splunk Search Head, Indexers, and Heavy Forwarders. In previous versions NFO events were inserted into index [flowintegrator]. To use or continue using custom index for your *flow data, please perform the following:
    </p>
    <p>
      Go to Settings->Indexes and if the [flowintegrator] index is not present click on the New Index button, enter <pre><code>    flowintegrator</code></pre> into the Index Name field and click Save.
    </p>
    <p>
      Alternatively, if you have SSH access to your Splunk servers, please perform the following:
    </p>
    <p>
        <ol>
            <li>
                Create the file if it does not already exist:
                <pre>$SPLUNK_ROOT/etc/apps/TA-netflow/local/indexes.conf</pre>
                and add the following lines to it:
                <pre>[flowintegrator]
homePath    = $SPLUNK_DB/flowintegrator/db
coldPath    = $SPLUNK_DB/flowintegrator/colddb
thawedPath  = $SPLUNK_DB/flowintegrator/thaweddb</pre>
            </li>
            <li>
              Restart Splunk
            </li>
        </ol>
    </p>
    </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>