<dashboard version="1.1">
    <label>Scheduled Export of Indexed Data (SEND)  to File v1.3.7</label>
    
    <row>
        <panel>
            <html>

            <h1>Overview</h1>
            <p>
       
            This is a Splunk Modular Alert used to facilitate scheduled export of indexed data (SEND) to a file location<br/>

            The exported file is just a gzipped CSV of the search results that triggered the alert.<br/>

            The real intent of this add-on though is as an example for developers to follow to show how you can essentially leverage the Modular Alerts framework to perform a scheduled data output.<br/>

            Other types of outputs to consider implementing : ftp,scp,jms,kafka,aws,rdbms,datawarehouse,some other data storage or processing platform etc...<br/>

            The Python code in this App is dual 2.7/3 compatible.<br/>
            This version of the App enforces Python 3 for execution of the modular input script when running on Splunk 8+ in order to satisfy Splunkbase AppInspect requirements.<br/>
            If running this App on Splunk versions prior to 8 , then Python 2.7 will get executed.<br/>



            </p>

            <hr/>
            <h1>Enter your Activation Key</h1>

            <p>
             Before you start , ensure that you browse to the App's setup page (on the navigation menu above) and enter your Activation Key.<br/> 
             Visit <a href="http://www.baboonbones.com/#activation" target="_blank">http://www.baboonbones.com/#activation</a> to obtain a non-expiring key or trial key.        
            </p>

            <hr/>
            <h1>Encrypting Configuration Fields</h1>

            <p>
       
            If you require an encrypted credential in your configuration , then you can enter it on the App's setup page<br/>
            
            Then in your configration refer to it in the format <code>{encrypted:somekey}</code><br/>
            
            Where <code>somekey</code> is any value you choose to enter on the setup page to reference your credential.

            </p>

            <hr/>
            <h1>Quickstart</h1>

            <p>
       
            Browse to <a href="../../../en-US/manager/launcher/alert_actions" target="_blank">Alert Actions</a> to start setting up your Alerts.

            </p>
            
            <hr/>
            <h1>Developer</h1>

            <p>
       
            This App is built and supported by the team at <a href="https://www.baboonbones.com" target="_blank">BaboonBones</a>

            </p>

                                    
            </html>
        </panel>
    </row>
</dashboard>