<dashboard>
  
  <label>Introduction</label>


  <!-- First row of a single comment -->
  <row>

    <!-- Static content, remove upon editing-->
    <html>
      <div style='color:#311b92'>
      <h2><b>
		Unleash the Power of Splunk on Finances Management
        </b>
      </h2>
      </div>
      <h3>
        With the advances of technology and Big Data Analytics, it is now easy to keep a check on your finances. As easy as 1-2-3..!
      </h3>

      <h2>How?</h2>
      <ol>
<li>Keep a track of your or your Company's Finances in an Excel or Take an Export from your Finance Reporting Tool.</li>

<li>Categorize them into Income / Expenditure.</li>

<li>Categorize Income into various Types:
<ul>  
<li>Salary - Your fixed Salary (in case of personal use) or Sale (in case of company)</li>
<li>Interest - Any Interest which may or may not be a steady income source</li>
<li>Bonus - Any Extra Income is always welcome!</li>
  </ul>
</li>
<li>Also, further categorize Expenses into 3 Types:
<ul>  
<li>Category A - Which are inevitable</li>
<li>Category B - Which may not be entirely avoidable. But can have a bit of discretion!</li>
<li>Category C - Which can be avoided with reasonable discretion!</li>
  </ul>
</li>
<li>Provide Details and Amount Spent / Earned / Received.</li>

<li>Save the Excel as CSV and Load into Splunk as per the format with sourcetype = 'FinanceTracker' or place them in the Directory which Splunk is monitoring.</li>
<li>You can also upload your other statements like Credit Card Statements, Equity Holdings and your other Financial Statements. 
  Make sure that your Input have the below columns or are re-mapped in Splunk through Alias:
  <ul>
    <li>Type - With data as Income/Expenditure 
    </li>
    <li>Category - Category A / B / C for Expenses as explained above or Salary / Interest / Bonus for Income
    </li>
    <li>Details - Text Details of your Income / Expense
    </li>
    <li>Value - Monetary value of the transaction
    </li>
    
  </ul>
        </li>

  <li>Build up quick charts, pivots  to analyse the finances and take control!</li>      </ol>
    </html>
  <!-- End of static content -->

  </row>
  
  

</dashboard>