<dashboard>
  <label>Documentation</label>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <h2>eStreamer for Splunk Help</h2>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#prep">Preparation</a></li>
        <li><a href="#upgrading">Upgrading the App</a></li>
        <li><a href="#config">Configuration</a></li>
        <li><a href="#dash">Dashboards</a></li>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="#dash1">eStreamer Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash2">Sensor Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash3">Policy Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash4">Host Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash8">Flow Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash5">Intrusion Event Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash6">File / Malware Event Summary</a></li>
          <li><a href="#dash7">Correlation Event Summary</a></li>
        </ul>
        <li><a href="#search">Searching</a></li>
        <li><a href="#actions">Event Actions</a></li>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="#action1">eStreamer: Save PCAP</a></li>
          <li><a href="#action2">eStreamer: View Event</a></li>
          <li><a href="#action3">eStreamer: View Connection</a></li>
        </ul>
      </ul>
    </html>
  </row>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="prep" /><h2>Preparation</h2>
      <p>Please note this app was developed for, and tested on, Unix platforms only.
        Windows support is not currently available.</p>
      <p>After you install eStreamer for Splunk, there are several things that
        you need to verify to ensure your eStreamer client functions properly and
        communicates with the Defense Center.</p>
      <p>Begin by creating the client certificate for the Splunk server from the Defense
        Center web interface. You can accomplish by logging into the Defense Center with
        an Admin account and selecting <b>System > Local > Registration</b>, then
        clicking the <b>Create Client</b> button. Sourcefire recommends that you use the
        IP address of the Splunk server rather than its hostname. The password is
        optional. Download the pkcs12 certificate and copy it onto the Splunk server.
        </p>
      <p>If you are wanting to collect flow/connection data, connection logging must
        be enabled in the Access Control Policy rules where the logging is desired. This
        also goes for the Security Intelligence events -- logging must be enabled on the
        Security Intelligence tab of the Access Control Policy.</p>
      <p>Next, you must validate that the required Perl modules are on the system. The
        following Perl modules are required for the eStreamer client to run:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Getopt::Long</li>
        <li>Socket</li>
        <li>IO::Socket::SSL</li>
        <li>NetAddr::IP</li>
        <li>Storable</li>
        <li>Socket6                     - Only required if IPv6 is used</li>
        <li>IO::Socket::INET6     - Only required if IPv6 is used</li>
      </ul>
      <p>It is recommended to use the package management system of your OS/distribution to
        install these modules before relying on CPAN.</p>
      <p>Next, you must validate that the eStreamer client functions correctly. Access
        the Splunk server terminal and navigate to the eStreamer for Splunk app directory.
        Next, enter the bin directory (<tt>$SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/eStreamer/bin/</tt>). From
        this directory, run the eStreamer client as follows:</p>
      <pre>./estreamer_client.pl</pre>
      <p>You should see the usage options present themselves. If you see errors, that
        means a required Perl module is missing.  Look at the error message to determine
        which module is needed and install it. Continue this process until the client
        runs without errors.</p>
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="upgrading" /><h2>Upgrading the App</h2>
      <p>Because the app is not hosted on the Splunk Apps site, new version notifications
        will not occur within Splunk.  Periodically visit the
        <a href="http://apps.splunk.com/app/1629/">app page</a> on the Splunk Apps site to
        see if there is a new version available.</p>
      <p>Before installing an upgrade to the app, it is recommended to disable the eStreamer
        client prior to the upgrade and to wait for it to stop before continuing.  This can
        be done from the app Setup page.  Ensure sure the "Upgrade app" check box is
        selected when installing the app package.  Once the upgrade has been completed, and
        Splunk restarted, the client can be re-enabled from the Setup page.</p>
    </html>
  </row>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="config" /><h2>Configuration</h2>
      <p>After you have prepared the Splunk server as described above, you can configure
        the app. You can reach the Setup page for the app in several ways
        (<a href="/manager/eStreamer/apps/local/eStreamer/setup?action=edit"
        target="_blank">including this link</a>) and then configure the app.</p>
      <p>The Setup page includes all of the details associated with the app, including
        how the eStreamer client connects to the Sourcefire Defense Center, such as
        Defense Center IP address, IP protocol (v4 or v6), the port, and the pkcs12
        certificate details. Enter the details as appropriate, making sure to provide
        the full path to the pkcs12 certificate on the Splunk server.</p>
      <p>There are three log options that are unchecked by default; <b>Log packets</b>,
        <b>Log flows</b>, and <b>Log metadata</b>. Packet logs make the packets
        associated with intrusion events easily accessible directly from Splunk
        searches but can consume large amounts of disk space quickly. The flow logs
        provide connection-level detail for the traffic traversing the network. The
        metadata logs show some of the eStreamer log detail, but don't directly
        provide value for event analysis.</p>
      <p>After you complete the configuration, you can clear the <b>Disable eStreamer
        client</b> checkbox. Until the app is configured, this should remain checked.</p>
      <p>At this point the app has been configured, and the eStreamer client should
        start within a minute or so. This is where you should start monitoring the
        eStreamer client for possible issues. The <b>Help</b> menu in the app includes a
        <b>Client Status</b> item that will provide you with a view of the status
        messages from the eStreamer client check script.</p>
    </html>
  </row>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="dash" /><h2>Dashboards</h2>
      <p>There are five dashboards provided by the app. Each of them gives a different
        high-level view of the data being provided by eStreamer from the Defense Center.
        It's important to note that each of the dashboards has a time selector at the top
        of the screen that allows for a change of the time period represented in the
        dashboard. Below is a brief description of each of the dashboards:</p>
      
      <a name="dash1" /><h4>eStreamer Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard provides an overview of the state of the eStreamer client, counts
        of the important eStreamer records being seen, and a timeline view of the records
        coming into Splunk.</p>

      <a name="dash2" /><h4>Sensor Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the distribution of events across the managed devices and
        security zones that are defined on each device. At the bottom of the dashboard is
        a sorted list of each device, and its associated interfaces and security zones.
        The devices with the most hits are displayed first.</p>

      <a name="dash3" /><h4>Policy Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the distribution of events across the access control
        policies, access control policy rules, and intrusion policies. This middle of
        the dashboard is a sorted list of each device, and its associated policies and
        rules. The devices with the most hits are displayed first. The bottom of the
        dashboard provides the distribution of events across the correlation policies
        and rules.</p>

      <a name="dash4" /><h4>Host Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the geographic region of the source and destination
        addresses involved in events, where possible. It's important to note that IP
        addresses in the RFC1918 space, or other reserved block, will not properly map.
        Next come sorted lists of the most frequently involved source and destination
        addresses, then a sorted list showing the most frequently involved source and
        destination address pairs. Lastly comes the most frequently involved ports, both
        as a source and a destination.</p>

      <a name="dash8" /><h4>Flow Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows detail about network connections being seen by the sensors.
        It provides a breakdown by application protocols, client applications, web
        applications, and detail about sensor, policy, and rule hit distributions.</p>

      <a name="dash5" /><h4>Intrusion Event Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the timeline of events coming into Splunk, as well as the
        distribution of events across the devices, priorities, impacts, and IPS block
        results. At the bottom of the dashboard is a sorted list of the most frequently
        hit signatures and signature classifications.</p>

      <a name="dash6" /><h4>File / Malware Event Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the timeline of events coming into Splunk, as well as the
        distribution of events across the devices, actions, disposition, and file types.
        At the bottom of the dashboard is a sorted list of the most frequently seen
        files.</p>

      <a name="dash7" /><h4>Correlation Event Summary</h4>
      <p>This dashboard shows the timeline of events coming into Splunk, as well as the
        distribution of events across the devices, policies, event types, and blocks.
        At the bottom of the dashboard is a sorted list of the most frequently seen
        correlations.</p>
    </html>
  </row>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="search" /><h2>Searching</h2>
      <p>eStreamer for Splunk puts logs into a dedicated index named estreamer. This
        means that searches against the eStreamer data must use <tt>index=estreamer</tt>.
        There are also two distinct source types associated with this app:
        <tt>eStreamer</tt> and <tt>client_check</tt>. All eStreamer logs use the
        <tt>eStreamer</tt> source type, where only eStreamer client status messages use
        the <tt>client_check</tt> source type.</p>
      <p>The <b>Search</b> menu provides quick access the different event searches, as well as
        IP address, port, and user profiling searches.</p>
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>
    <html>
      <a name="actions" /><h2>Event Actions</h2>
      <p>eStreamer for Splunk adds three items to the <b>Event Actions</b> menu available
        in searches:</p>
        
      <a name="action1" /><h4>eStreamer: Save PCAP</h4>
      <p>This action will only work for PACKET eStreamer records
        (<tt>rec_type_simple=PACKET</tt>). It takes the values of the <tt>event_id</tt>
        and <tt>packet</tt> fields and decodes the hex encoded packet, returning a PCAP
        as a downloadable file using the event ID for the filename (for example,
        5110.pcap). It is important to note that the <b>Log packets</b> setting must be
        enabled for this Event Action to be of use.</p>
        
      <a name="action2" /><h4>eStreamer: View Event</h4>
      <p>This action will work for any log containing the <tt>event_id</tt> field.  It
        will open a new search looking for any logs with the same event ID value.</p>
        
      <a name="action3" /><h4>eStreamer: View Connection</h4>
      <p>This action will work for any log containing the <tt>instance_id</tt> and
        <tt>connection_id</tt> fields.  It will open a new search looking for any
        logs with the same connection values.</p>
    </html>
  </row>
  
</dashboard>