<dashboard>
  <label>Getting Data In</label>
  <description></description>

  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>Getting Data In</h2>

        <p>In Splunk 6.2, we’ve completely remodeled the pages and workflows for adding data, including new features like Forwarder Inputs and a new version of Data Preview.</p>

        <br/>

        <h3>Consolidated Workflow</h3>
        <p>We’ve made it much easier to find your way to the appropriate input configuration. Instead of selecting from a confusing list of sources, start with a simple choice of “upload, monitor, or forward” and you’ll find yourself in a simple wizard-style workflow of defining the appropriate parameters for the data you want to add.</p>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_2_overview/images/GDI_Splash.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;"/>

        <br/><br/><br/>

        <h3>Forwarder Inputs</h3>
        <p>With Forwarder Inputs, you are able to push input configurations to Splunk instances configured as deployment clients. Simply select one or more forwarders, provide a group name, and you’ll be able to create data inputs on them in the same way you create inputs through the UI on your indexers.</p>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_2_overview/images/GDI_Forwarders.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;"/>

        <br/><br/><br/>

        <h3>New Data Preview:</h3>
        <p>The new data preview utility will make it easier for you to create the right sourcetype for your data. In the advanced section, you’ll be able to choose a charset from a list, and see how changes you make to your sourcetype are reflected in props.conf.</p>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_2_overview/images/GDI_Preview.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;"/>

        <br/><br/><br/>

        <h3>Sourcetype categories and descriptions</h3>

        <p>In order to better choose the appropriate sourcetype when adding data we built a new sourcetype picker, which includes categories and descriptions. To add categories and descriptions to your sourcetypes, modify the sourcetype_metadata.conf file. [docs link]</p>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_2_overview/images/GDI_sourcetypes.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;"/>

        <br/><br/><br/>

        <h3>Contextual FAQs</h3>

        <p>Not sure what the recommended configurations are, or how to use a specific parameter? We’ve got you covered, with FAQs on each step of the way while you add data to Splunk!</p>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_2_overview/images/GDI_FAQ.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;"/>

       

      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

</dashboard>