<dashboard  stylesheet="help.css">
  <label>Help</label>
 
  <row>
    <panel>
      <title>FAQ for Check Point Analytics App for Checkpoint</title>
      <html>
      <div id="QA">
	  
      <ul>
        
      <li>
      <span>Why i am not getting data in "Syslog Message" tab?</span><br/>
        
      <p>This may be because sourcetype of your syslog is different from "qos_syslog". You can follow any of the below steps to make this work</p>
      <p>Option 1. Create an inputs.conf file in "$SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/CheckPointAnalyticsAppbyQOS/default/" and add below line to same file<br/>
         [udp:514]<br/>
         sourcetype=qos_syslog<br/>
      </p>
      <p>Option 2. You can monitor you UDP port 514 for syslog and give sourcetype name as "qos_syslog". Document for same is available here <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Data/Monitornetworkports">http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/Data/Monitornetworkports</a></p>
      <p>Option 3. Install our Add-on <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/2996/">https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/2996/</a><br/>
		This will open UDP port 514 automatically and give its sourcetype as "qos_syslog".</p>
      
      </li>
      <br/> <br/>
      
      
      <li>
      <span>Which Checkpoint Blades(Features) are supported by this app?</span><br/>
        
      <p>This App currently supports Firewall, IPS and Application/URL Control Blades.
        If you want us to add more blades Please mail us at splunk@qos.co.in</p>
      
      </li>
      <br/> <br/>
	  
      <li>
      <span>Is Checkpoint LEA app mandatory for this app to work?</span><br/>
         
	  <p>No Check Point LEA Add-on is not mandatory for this App.
         There are two methods by which one can capture Check Point Firewall logs on Splunk.</p>
      <p>Option 1. [Recommended]  => <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1454/">https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1454/</a> <br/>
 		 This Add-on uses the index file created using Checkpoint LEA app. </p>
      <p>Option 2. <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/2996/">https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/2996/</a><br/>
		This Add-on should be used when Splunk indexer is running on Windows. We developed this App because Check Point LEA is not available on Windows.
	  </p>
      </li>
          
      <br/><br/>
              
	  <li>
      <span>I need step by step document to install Checkpoint LEA app or Check Point syslog Add-on on my Splunk.</span><br/>
             
      <p> Please check following link and follow the steps mentioned in the blog.<br/></p>
      <p><a href="http://qostechnology.in/blog/integrate-splunk-with-checkpoint-managementlog-server//">
			   http://qostechnology.in/blog/integrate-splunk-with-checkpoint-managementlog-server//</a><br/></p>
      <p>If you want to send Check Point logs via syslog please check the following link.<br/></p>
      <p><a href="http://qostechnology.in/blog/check-point-tracker-logs-to-external-syslog-server/">
			   http://qostechnology.in/blog/check-point-tracker-logs-to-external-syslog-server/</a><br/></p>
      <p>Alternately for more information you can read splunk's official documentation.<br/></p>
      <p><a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/OPSEC-LEA/3.1.0/Install/InstalltheSplunkTechnologyAdd-onforCheckPointOPSECLEA">
                    http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/OPSEC-LEA/3.1.0/Install/InstalltheSplunkTechnologyAdd-onforCheckPointOPSECLEA</a></p>
      </li>
         
      <br/> <br/>
      
      <li>
	  <span>Is this Free app or paid app?</span><br/>
    
      <p>This app is absolutely free to use and will never be charged in future. QOS will launch a new paid version of this app very soon which will have many more stuffs and powerful analytics on Checkpoint Logs. Stay tuned.</p>
         
	  </li>
         
      <br/><br/>
       <li>
       <span>I need help as I am facing some issues with this app? Whom shall I contact?</span><br/>
	   <p>Please email  the issue in detail with appropriate screenshots at splunk@qos.co.in and we promise to get back to you in less than 48 hrs.</p>
       </li>
       <br/><br/>
      <li>
	  <span>How can I give some suggestions to improve this app.</span><br/>
      <p>We will be more than happy to listen from our customers. Feel free to drop your emails at splunk@qos.co.in</p>
      </li>
      <br/> <br/>
        
	  <li>
      <span>Dashboard appears to be too slow. Is there any problem?</span><br/>
         
      <p>Here is the formula which determines the number of concurrent searches one can run at any point of time.</p>
      <p>the total number of concurrent searches =  base_max_searches + (# of cpus) * (max_searches_per_cpu)</p>
      <p>base_max_searches and max_searches_per_cpu is defined in limits.conf file on your splunk server.</p>
      </li>
         
      </ul>
      </div>
     <br/>
        
  </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>