<dashboard>
  
  <label>Cacti Poller Intro</label>


  
  <row>

    
    <html>
      
      <h2>
      Welcome to the MKAdvantage Cacti Poller Portal.  This portal will allow you to do the following:
      </h2>
      <ul>
        <li>View the health/status of all of your Cacti servers that are reporting up to Splunk</li>
          <li>Create consolidated reports and metrics across several monitored targets on several Cacti Servers</li>
          <li>Create alerts based on thresholds generated by group reporting</li>
          <li>Enrich data based on target information (use lookup tables)</li>
      </ul>
      
    </html>
  </row>

  <row>

    
    <html>
      
      <h2>
        Installation Instructions:
      </h2>
      <ul>
        <li>Install Universal Forwarders on each Cacti server.  Please refer to the docs.splunk.com website and search for universal forwarders. </li>
          <li>Modify your indexers to receive data if you haven't done so already.</li>
        <li>Optional:  Create two indexes called cacti_system and cacti_perf.  This will keep your data separate from the rest of your data that may have different retention periods.</li>
          <li>Modify the inputs.conf file and specify your host, index, etc.  Optional:  We created two indexes, cacti_system for cacti poller data and cacti_perf for the perf data.</li>
          <li>Deploy your inputs.conf to your forwarders.</li>
        <li>In the $SPLUNK_HOME/bin directory, you will find makeperflog.pl.  Put this somewhere on each of your Cacti servers.  Please open this file and read the comments.</li>
        <li>In makeperflog.pl, make sure your file locations and log locations are where you want them to be.  Change them if necessary.  Also update the bottom portion if you want something other than Advanced Ping</li>
        <li>On each of your Cacti servers, update your /etc/cron.d/cacti to run the makeperflog.pl.  Schedule it to run as often as your pollers run.  This will do an rrdtool info, pull your data and create your log that the forwarder will send to Splunk.</li>
        <li>If you change the log location inside of makeperflog.pl, MAKE SURE YOUR inputs.conf IS MONITORING THIS LOG!</li>
        <li>Contact contact_us@mkadvantage.com if you have questions or need help implementing this solution.</li>
       </ul>
      
    </html>
  </row>

      
</dashboard>