<dashboard>
  <label>Introduction</label>
  <!-- First row of a single comment -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h1><div style='color:#311b92'><b>orgSecure</b></div></h1>
      <h3><div style='color:#311b92'>
        Secure your Organisation from Threats Within</div>
      </h3>
        <div>orgSecure works on two Key Priciples of effective Threat detections:<br/><br/>
          <ol>
            <li>Detecting User Behaviour Anomalies using Historic Usage Patterns</li>
            <li>Active Monitoring of User Activities, Assets and Confidential Files</li>
          </ol>
        </div>
        <br/>
        <div>
          orgSecure uses complex statistical techniques to create baseline envelops for users which determine their normal usage patterns. Any deviation from the envelops for consecutive periods are reported and should be investigated to prevent loss to the organisation due to the 'Insider' Threats. 
        </div>
        <br/>
        <b>Key Features:</b><br/>
        <ul>
<li>Detect Deviation in User behaviour through configurable Baseline Envelop 
          </li><li>Detect Anomalies through User Normal Login/Logoff pattern and Weekend usage.
          </li><li>Detect employees who have greater dependencies through their Holiday taking pattern.
          </li><li>Detect Breaches through Data Transfer outside organisation through external sources like Wikileaks, File Sharing Sites and through email to public domain 
          </li><li>Detect Abnormal Asset usage of employees like irregular / suspicious PC access, malicious softwares, and abnormal Removable Media usage.
          </li><li>Monitor User Profile through Hierarchy Analysis and Psychometric Tests
          </li><li>Monitor User Usage through Logs from different sources like email, web access, login/lgoff patterns, PC accessed and Removable Media access.
          </li><li>Monitor User Usage through a unified view of different sources in a single window to get patterns out of the chronological events.
          </li><li>Monitor Assets: PC - Through powerful visualization, understand who uses the PC as well as what activities are performed
          </li><li>Monitor Assets:Files - Through powerful visualization, understand who accesses critical files, copies them as well as emails them.
          </li>
        </ul>
    </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>