<dashboard>
  <label>Introduction</label>
  <!-- First row of a single comment -->
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h1><div style='color:#311b92'><b>Energy Scan</b></div></h1>
      <h3><div style='color:#311b92'>
        Energy Scan is an Analytics Solution to monitor, analyse and optimize your Energy Load Profile. Connect your Telemetry System Feed/Logs to obtain real-time information to manage your company's Energy Load Profile.
        </div>
      </h3>

        <b>Key Features:</b>
        <ul>
<li>Monitor Energy Demand in Real Time
          </li><li>Get Insights from Historical Demand Profile to optimize Energy Distribution
          </li><li>Geo-Analytics to obtain geography-aware Insights
          </li><li>Can be used to understand Energy Demand for various utilities including Electricity, Water and Gas
          </li><li>Connect your real-time Telemetry Systems to gain real-time Energy Demand Information
          </li><li>Data input can be as granular as end-customer level details to understand market segmentation and plan campaigns
          </li><li>Gain insights on consumer consumption pattern to optimize costs and plan Energy Generation/Abstraction in advance
          </li>
        </ul>
        <h3><div style='color:#311b92'>Dashboards:</div></h3>
        <b>Company Overview:</b> 
        <ul><li>
Gain a high-level Information about the Energy Demand across the company. 
          </li><li>Gain insights on distribution of Energy requirements. for e.g. Heating, HVAC, Lighting, Cooling, etc
</li></ul>
        <b>Company Analytics: </b>
          <ul><li>
Obtain insights on Energy Demand across various stations and geography
</li><li>Determine stations with maximum demand based on time factor
</li></ul>
        <b>Company Energy Visualization:</b>
            <ul><li>
Energy Demand Insights through interactive Visualizations 
</li></ul>
        <b>Company Geo-Analytics:</b>
            <ul><li>
Visualize Energy Demand on Maps and compare Stations 
</li></ul>
        <b>Station Monitoring:</b>
              <ul><li>
Monitor Energy Demands in real-time
</li><li>Understand current demand and peak demands
</li><li>Gain Insights on distribution and time factor
</li></ul>
        <b>Station Performance:</b>
                <ul><li>
Analyse Station Demand using Historical Data
</li><li>Understand Daily Energy Load Profile to gain insights on consumer consumption pattern
</li><li>Understand Monthly Peak Energy Requirements
</li></ul>
        <b>Station Analytics:</b>
                  <ul><li>
Understand Energy Profile based on various factors including Weekend/Weekdays/Seasons/Time Period
</li><li>Gain Insights on consumer consumption pattern based on these factors, which can help plan Energy Generation/Abstraction in advance
</li></ul>
        <b>Station Comparison:</b>
                    <ul><li>
Compare different Stations to understand changes in Demand Patterns
</li><li>Compare data of a single Station under different conditions
</li></ul>
        <b>Reports:</b>
                      <ul><li>
Energy Load Profile Reports - Monthly and Hourly
</li></ul>
          <b>Custom Search and Pivot:</b>
                      <ul><li>
Use the power of Splunk to create your own insights
                        </li></ul>
    </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>