<dashboard>
  <label>Custom Alert Actions</label>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
         <h2>Custom Alert Actions</h2>
        
        <p>Custom alerts actions enable packaged integrations with popular third-party applications to automate workflows and improve efficiency.</p>

         <br/>
           
        <p>Custom alert actions provide a framework for developers to build, package, and publish alert actions for native integration into Splunk.  For admins, these alert actions can be downloaded, installed, configured, and managed entirely through the user interface.</p>

        <br/>
        
        <p>More specifically, the custom alert actions framework provides:</p>
        
        <ul>
          
          <li><b><i>Packaging</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Custom alert actions can be packaged and distributed as apps
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>UI Integration</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Developers can build custom html forms to accept user inputs into the alert script.  This custom UI is rendered to users upon selecting the action in the alert workflow.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Management</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Admin-level management to enable/disable, view usage stats, and more.  This can be found in Settings > Knowledge > Alert actions.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Permissions</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Access controls for each alert action to enable for all or select roles.  By default, alert actions should be global.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Logging</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Logs both splunkd process level as well as script-level events to internal index.  Easy access to these logs via the Alert actions manager page.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Input Validation </i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Perform user input validation on save of a given alert.  Controlled via restmap handler.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Dynamic Parameter Support (w/ token substitution) </i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Define parameters to be passed on script invocation.  Available token substitution for 1st result and search/job/server information.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Multi-platform Compatibility </i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Package multiple scripts to run based on platform type (Windows, Linux)
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Secured Storage of Credentials </i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Encrypt sensitive credentials on disk, with access methods to read/write from your alert script
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Ad-Hoc Invocation </i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Invoke directly from query string or workflow actions for testing or targeted use cases
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Setup/Configuration</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Leverage the app setup.xml to persist global-level script parameters.  These parameters can also be layered with invocation-specific parameters.
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

          <li><b><i>Runtime Arguments</i></b>
            <ul>
              <li>
                Specify runtime parameters (ex., java interpreter and argument flags)
              </li>
            </ul>
          </li>

        </ul>
        
        <br/><br/>
        
        <h2>Seamless UI integration into alert workflow</h2>

        <br/>

        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/alert_actions_1.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:600px"/>
        
        <br/><br/>

        <p><i>Alert actions dropdown presents users with all installed and available alert actions.</i></p>

        <br/><br/>

        <h2>Developer-defined UI to accept input configuration parameters</h2>

        <br/>
        
        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/alert_actions_2.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;width:700px"/>

        <br/><br/>

        <p><i>Developers build html for inline rendering within alert workflow to accept/bind user input parameters to invocation arguments.</i></p>
        
        <br/><br/>

        <h2>Alert actions management UI</h2>

        <br/>
        
        <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/alert_actions_3.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;width:1100px"/>
        
        <br/><br/>

        <p><i>Admins can manage all installed alert actions (enable/disable, permission, view log events, link to app-level setup page.</i></p>

        <br/><br/>
        
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>