<dashboard>
  <label>Developer Guidance</label>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
         <h2>Developer Guidance</h2>

         <p>The Splunk developer platform enables developers to take advantage of their web development skills and the same underlying technologies that power the core Splunk Enterprise product to build exciting new apps and solutions that address your specific use cases and technologies.
         </p>

         <p>The Splunk Developer Guidance includes two reference apps and associated applied engineering guidance to help you become productive, competent and successful in building, testing and deploying comprehensive Splunk solutions. The reference apps are complete, end-to-end real-world apps build together with our partners which are meant to showcase various underlying technologies as well as good and proven practices &amp; patterns.
         </p>

         <br/>

         <h3>Splunk Reference App – PAS</h3>
        
         <p>The Pluggable Auditing System (PAS) app and the accompanying guidance will help you learn how to develop apps for Splunk Enterprise. This end-to-end app implements real-world use cases. The presented experience includes software development, testing, packaging and publishing a Splunk app.  The reference app is intended to enable an organization monitor various document repositories. Managers and auditors can use the app to see who has looked at, updated, modified, deleted, or downloaded documents or other artifacts from various sources. 
         </p>

         <p>Note: The app also comes pre-installed in the Splunk Cloud Sandbox.
         </p>

         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/developer_guidance_1.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:600px"/>

         <br/><br/>

         <p>More details:
         <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1934/" target="_blank">https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1934/</a>
         </p> 

         <br/><br/>
         
         <h3>Splunk Reference App – Auth0</h3>

         <p>Splunk Reference App for Auth0 pulls your logs and gives you an admin dashboard to monitor usage activity on Auth0. Default views include: signups, successful logins, geo distribution of your users, and more. Auth0 is an identity management service, built for developers. It provides SSO for custom, social and enterprise accounts.
         </p>

         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/developer_guidance_2.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:600px"/>

         <br/><br/>

         <p>More details:
         <a href="https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1884/" target="_blank">https://splunkbase.splunk.com/app/1884/</a>
         </p> 

         <br/><br/>

         <h3>Splunk Developer Guide</h3>

         <p>This guide describes a journey undertaken by an engineering team and is intended to give you an insight into how to set about developing Splunk apps, to recommend some good and proven practices, and to provide a useful reference when you come to build your own Splunk apps. 
         </p>

         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/developer_guidance_3.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:300px"/>

         <br/><br/>

         <p>More details:
         <a href="http://dev.splunk.com/goto/devguide " target="_blank">http://dev.splunk.com/goto/devguide</a>
         </p>

        <br/><br/>

        
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>