<dashboard>
  <label>Field Extractor Enhancement</label>
  <description>Simplified field extraction via delimiter and header selection. Displays field extractions within the event preview.</description>

  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
		<p>In Splunk 6.3, we’ve added a number of new features to the Advanced Field Extractor to both improve the accuracy of extractions as well as make the process of creating fields even easier.</p>

      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/field_extractor_enhancements-1.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

		<h2>Delimiter Mode</h2>
 
		<p>The Advanced Field Extractor’s new “Delimiter Mode” provides an easy and effective method for specifying field names for the values in your delimited data. Simply choose the appropriate delimiter type for your data, and then click the field values in the sample event to assign a field name to them. Use the “other” option to specify a custom delimiter. Your data’s timestamp, host, and sourcetype fields will not be altered.</p>
      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/field_extractor_enhancements-2.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>
 
		<h2>Existing Fields</h2>

		<p>We added this helpful feature to assist with the extraction process by letting you view field extractions that have already been defined for your data. </p>

		<p>Existing extractions are displayed by default as outlines surrounding values within the sample and previewed events. If they look correct, then you don’t need to extract them again.</p>
      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/field_extractor_enhancements-3.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>
		 
		<p>To enable/disable existing field outlines, click the “Existing Fields” button:</p>
      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/field_extractor_enhancements-4.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

		<p>Toggle the checkboxes to show or hide the outlines:</p>
      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/field_extractor_enhancements-5.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

 
       

      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

</dashboard>