<dashboard>
  <label>HTTP Event Collector</label>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
         <h2>HTTP Event Collector</h2>
        
         <p>A new simple, secure, highly performant and scalable endpoint for developers to send JSON application events.</p>

         <ul>
          <li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
          <li><a href="#using">Using the collector</a></li>
          <li><a href="#enabling">Enabling the collector</a></li>
          <li><a href="#creating">Creating a token</a></li>
          <li><a href="#sending">Sending events to HTTP Event Collector</a></li>
         </ul>

         <br/>

         <a name="introduction"><h2>Introduction</h2></a>

         <div style="margin-left:20px">

         <p>In Splunk 6.3 we’ve introduced an exciting new feature for developers to use to send application events directly to Splunk over HTTP/HTTPs without requiring a lot of heavy lifting: the new HTTP Event Collector (HEC).</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_1.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>

         <p>The new HTTP Event Collector uses a new token-based authentication model that is not tied to a Splunk user. In the Data Inputs manager you can create one or more tokens. Once you have a valid token, you can easily send events from your applications using any HTTP Client, logging libraries, or a tool like curl.</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_2.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>         

         <br/>
         
         <p>HEC is designed for scale. You can start with a single deployment, using it out of the box, without deploying anything additional. As the number of clients sending events or number of events grow, it can be scaled out to support potentially hundreds of thousands or even millions of events.</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_3.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <br/>

         </div>

         <a name="using"><h2>Using the collector</h2></a>

         <div style="margin-left:20px">


         <p>Below is a quick walkthrough to get you up to speed using the collector.</p>

         <br/>

         <a name="enabling"><h3>Enabling the collector</h3></a>

         <div style="margin-left:20px">

         <p>By default HTTP Event Collector is disabled. You can enable it by going to <strong>Settings>Data Inputs&gt;HTTP Event Collector</strong>. Then click the <strong>Global Settings</strong> button in the corner.</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_4.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>

         <p>This will bring up a configuration screen for HEC, which is disabled by default. Click the Enable button, and then click <strong>Save</strong>.</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_5.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <br/>
         
         </div>

         <a name="creating"><h3>Creating a token</h3></a>
         
         <div style="margin-left:20px">

         <p>Once HEC is enabled, you can create a token for sending events. Click on the <strong>New Token</strong> button:</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_6.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <p>This will bring up the Add Data page where you can define a new token.</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_7.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <p>Enter a name for the token, and optionally complete the other fields. When you’re done, click <strong>Next</strong>.</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_8.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <p>From this screen you can further configure your token. Select “main” from the <strong>Default Index</strong> pop-up menu. Then click <strong>Review</strong> to review the details of your new token.</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_9.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <p>Click <strong>Submit</strong> and the token is created.</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_10.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>

         <p>Right-click on the string in the <strong>Token Value</strong> field and copy the value to the clipboard. You’ll use the token value when you send your HTTP request to HEC.</p>

         <p>Click the <strong>Start Searching</strong> button to bring up a search for events for your new token.</p>


         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_11.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
        
         </div>

         <a name="sending"><h3>Sending events to HTTP Event Collector</h3></a>

         <div style="margin-left:20px">

         <p>Once you have a token, you can easily send events to HTTP Event Collector. Here is a cURL statement you can use from the terminal to test out your token. Replace &lt;host&gt; with your hostname and &lt;token&gt; with the token that you copied to the clipboard.</p>

         <pre style="margin-left:30px"><![CDATA[curl -k https://<host>:8088/services/collector -H 'Authorization: Splunk <token>' -d '{"event":"Hello Event Collector"}']]></pre>

         <br/>

         <p>Below is a screen shot showing sending an event via cURL:</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_12.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>
         <p>After sending the event, head back to the Search page, and click the magnifier to search again. Once the search completes, you should see the new event that you have just sent. Congratulations, you have now used HTTP Event Collector!</p>

         <div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/http_event_collector_13.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

         <br/>

         </div>

         </div>

        
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>