<dashboard>
  <label>Mobile Access</label>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
         <h2>Introduction</h2>
        
         <p>
Splunk Mobile Access delivers a mobile-optimized version of Splunk Enterprise/Cloud dashboards, drill downs, reports and search. Splunk Administrators can choose the dashboards and reports available to mobile users. Users can set favorite dashboards and reports to quickly focus on the most relevant data. Mobile Access is enabled by the Splunk Mobile App – available for free from the Apple App Store, Google Play Store, or your in-house MDM marketplace. Once an access port is enabled by your Splunk administrator, the app can be used freely with your company data. The Splunk Add-On for Mobile Access should also be installed to enable many key features. See below for details.
         </p>
         
         <br/>
         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/product_overview.png" style="margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto;" />
         <br/>
         <br/>

         <ul>
          <li>Splunk Mobile Access gives you a powerful way to view and analyze Splunk dashboards, reports and real-time alerts on Apple iOS and Android devices</li>
          <li>Monitor key performance indicators from iOS and Android devices</li>
          <li>Receive and act on real-time business and operational alerts</li>
          <li>Easily view and analyze dashboards and reports</li>
          <li>Annotate and share performance data with colleagues</li>
         </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">Deployment Option 1: Connect to Splunk Server Directly (Limited Functionality)</h2>
         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/connect_directly.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:10px; width:150px;" align="left"/>
         <ul style="margin-left: 180px;">
           <li>If splunkd port is accessible by mobile app, devices can connect to Splunk server and work immediately</li>
           <li>Functionality Limits:
           	<ul style="margin-left: 20px;">
           	  <li>No dashboard/reporting filtering configuration</li>
           	  <li>No mobile notification</li>
           	  <li>No SSO or DMZ support</li>
           	</ul>
           </li>
         </ul>
        
      </html>
    </panel>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">Deployment Option 2:  Connect to Splunk Server via Splunk Add-on (Recommended)</h2>
          <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/connect_via_addon.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:200px;" align="left"/>
          <ul style="margin-left: 250px;">
           <li>Download Splunk Add-on for Mobile Access from SplunkBase</li>
           <li>Install in Splunk Search Head; search head clustering is supported</li>
           <li>Enable mobile device to connect to Splunk Web </li>
           <li>Supports:</li>
           	<ul style="margin-left: 20px;">
           	  <li>Configuration of mobile access settings, dashboards and reports</li>
           	  <li>Mobile notifications</li>
           	  <li>SSO and MDM</li>
           	  <li>DMZ deployment</li>
           	</ul>
          </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">Deployment Option 3: DMZ Deployment with Splunk Add-on for Mobile Access</h2>
         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/dmz.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:300px;" align="left"/>
         <ul style="margin-left: 350px;">
		 <li>Install and configure Splunk Add-on for Mobile Access (Same as deployment option 2)</li>
		 <li>Install reverse proxy server in DMZ</li>
		 <li>Configure reverse proxy sever – Apache, Nginx, IIS, etc</li>
         </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">MDM Wrapping for In-house App Store</h2>
         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/mdm.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:150px;" align="left"/>
         <ul style="margin-left: 200px;">
         <li>To support in-house app store,  Splunk Mobile App supports MDM wrapping</li>
         <li>Verified with Good Technology 2.5 and Mocana MAP</li>
         <li>Only for iOS App</li>
         <li>Contact Mobile Team if you plan to wrap Mobile App (mobile@splunk.com)</li>
         </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">Leverage your Single Sign-On Service</h2>
         <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/sso.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:300px;" align="left"/>
         <ul style="margin-left: 350px;">
         <li>For customers who already use Single Sign-On (SSO) for Splunk Enterprise</li>
         <li>Mobile App can leverage the same authentication mechanism as Splunk Enterprise</li>
         <li>Verified SSO Services include: CAS 3.5.2, OpenAM 11.0.0, SAML</li>
         </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2 style="margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 20px;">Available on Apple App Store and Google Play</h2>
         <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/splunk-mobile-app/id848652190?ls=1&amp;mt=8">
           <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/apple_app_store.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:200px;" align="left"/>
         </a>
         <ul style="margin-left: 250px;">
         <li>iOS 7, 8, 9</li>
         <li>iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch</li>
         </ul>
         <br/>
         <br/>
         <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.splunk.mobile.access">
           <img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/mobile_access/google_play.png" style="margin-left:20px; margin-right:30px; width:200px;" align="left"/>
         </a>
         <ul style="margin-left: 250px;">
         <li>Android 4.3 and above</li>
         <li>Some verified devices include Google Nexus 5, Samsung S4 and Samsung S5 Android phones</li>
         </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>
