<dashboard>
  <label>Source Type Manager</label>
  <description>Create and manage sourcetype configurations independent of getting data in.</description>

  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
      	<p>Now introducing: the Source type manager! In Splunk 6.3 you can now view, edit, and create new source types.</p>

		<p><strong>Note: </strong>In order to access and use the Source type manager, you must have the capability “edit_sourcetypes” assigned to your login or role. This is capability is only assigned to the admin role by default. </p>

		<p><strong>Known issue:</strong> The “edit_sourcetypes” capability is not currently displaying in the capability list.</p>

      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/sourcetype_manager-1.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

		<h2>Source Type Listing</h2>

		<p>On the listing page, you can sort and filter source types by Name, Category, and App. To edit a sourcetype, click its name or the Edit action. To create a new sourcetype, click “New Source Type” (Note: you will not be able to supply a sample file for use with Data Preview)</p>

      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/sourcetype_manager-2.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>

		<h2>New source type &amp; Editing a source type</h2>
		<p>The source types editor page allows you to define a new source type or make changes the index-time parameters of an existing source type. The Advanced section allows you to specify <span class="code">props.conf</span> parameters and understand what the UI elements translate to. This functionality is very similar to what is available in Data Preview when adding data.</p>

      	<div><img src="/static/app/splunk_6_3_overview/images/sourcetype_manager-3.png" style="margin: 20px 0"/></div>


		<p><strong>Note:</strong> You can only define or edit source types local to a specific app directory in <span class="code">$SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps/</span>.  Because the options available here are index-time specific, the primary use case for this feature is to define configurations that exist on Splunk Indexers. You also cannot define or editor source types within a deployment app directory – Source type manager is not currently integrated with deployment server.</p>

		<p><strong>Known Issue:</strong> Selecting an “Indexed Extractions” method should present additional options depending on the method – allowing you to define parameters like a line number containing a header, or manual field/header information.</p>

       

      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>

</dashboard>