<dashboard version="1.1">
  <label>Introduction</label>
  <row>
   <panel> 
   <html>
     <table >
       <tbody>
	 <tr>
	   <td valign="top"> <img src="/static/app/Keyword/Autobahn_enablement-SideBanner_NewPnk.png" alt="Autobahn" width="300" height="50"/> </td>
	 </tr>
	 <tr><td>
<p>Welcome to the app to accelerate your autobahn experience. In this app, you'll find a simple way to view analytics for your data by simply typing in keyword terms into forms. What's a keyword? It could be any search term such as error, failure, exception, etc. All the app requires is that you have available data properly ingested into Splunk. This Keyword app can be installed on a standalone machine or a search head. Field extractions are not required. There are a series of dashboards listed below that you can use to analyze your data. The same dashboards are repeated in the Dashboards menu on top. Most dashboards follow the format that we list below, making it very easy to use this app. Happy Splunking!</p>
	   </td>
	 </tr>
	 <tr>
	   <td><img src="/static/app/Keyword/howTo.png" width="100%"></img></td>
	 </tr>
	 <tr><td>
	   <h3>Available Dashboards</h3>
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Top_Dashboard">Top Sources, Sourcetypes, or Hosts</a> for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Rare_Dashboard">Rare Sources, Sourcetypes, or Hosts</a> for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="top_punct_Dashboard">Top 10 Punctuations</a> for Keyword Search to Find Commonalities
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Rare_Punct_Dashboard">Rare Punctuations</a> for Keyword Search to Find Anomolies
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="EasyButton_Dashboard">Easy Triage</a> This finds issues, even without a keyword.
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Cluster_Dashboard">Clusters Similar Events</a> for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Outlier_Dashboard">Finds Sources, Sourcetypes, or Hosts</a> for Keyword Search counts that are outside the average plus N*standard deviation
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Slope_Dashboard">Shows the Slope</a> of the Occurrances of a Keyword
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Abstract_Dashboard">Show N Lines</a> per Multiline Event for Keyword Search 
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Baseline_Dashboard">Compare</a> this Week vs. Last Week for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Timewrap_Dashboard">Compare 3 Weeks</a> for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
	 <tr> <td>
	     <a href="Predict_Dashboard">Predict Future Counts</a> for Keyword Search
	 </td></tr>
       </tbody>
     </table>
   </html>
   </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>
