<dashboard stylesheet="comp_checker.css" version="1.1">
  <label>Home</label>
  <row>
    <panel id="compatibility">
      <html>
      <div id="compatibilityinfo">
          <b>"Current version of TA is not compatible with installed SANtricity Web Service Proxy. Please check Compatibility Matrix below."</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
      <div id="div_version"/>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
<b>About the App</b><br/>
The Splunk Performance App for NetApp E-Series/EF-Series provides visibility into the performance and health of NetApp E-Series and EF-Series storage systems.<br/>
To view the configuration of all arrays (storage systems) that are being monitored, choose the Configuration tab. Select a particular array to drill down further.<br/>
To view performance, choose the Performance tab and select an array. From there you can drill down to RAID Controllers, Dynamic Disk Pools or Volume Groups/Pools, Volumes, and Drives.<br/>
To view the Major Event Log maintained by a storage system, choose the Events tab and select an array or controller.<br/>
<p/>
<b>About the Add-on</b><br/>
To enable data collection, the "NetApp SANtricity Add-on for Splunk" is required. This separate application resides on a Splunk node to query the SANtricity Web Services Proxy for configuration, performance, and event data. The Add-on has two pages "Inputs" and "Configuration". Each instance of SANtricity Web Services Proxy must be configured as an "account" before any inputs (arrays to be monitored) can be added. Add an "account" by filling out the form with details specific to a particular SANtricity Web Services Proxy instance. "Inputs" must be added before data can be collected. "Inputs" are of two types: "NetApp ESeries Monitor" and "NetApp ESeries Register and Monitor". Choose "NetApp ESeries Monitor" to monitor an array that was previously added under management by a SANtricity Web Services Proxy instance (the WWN associated with the array is required). Otherwise, choose "NetApp ESeries Register and Monitor" and provide the IP addresses and administrative password of an array to add it under management with a SANtricity Web Services Proxy instance for the first time.
<p/>
<b>About Upgrading the Add-on version</b><br/>
<i>NOTE: These steps required only for upgrading the Add-on and Performance App from 1.0.0 to any higher version (2.0.0 or 3.0.0)</i><br/>
Additional steps are required after upgrading the Add-on and Performance App using the Splunk GUI. Provided in the package are two scripts, upgrade_from_1.0.0_to_2.0.0.py and upgrade_helper_from_1.0.0_to_2.0.0.py. Run both scripts in following manner. First, navigate to the bin folder of the add-on by executing "cd $SPLUNK_HOME$/etc/apps/TA-netapp_eseries/bin". Then execute "$SPLUNK_HOME$/bin/splunk cmd python upgrade_from_1.0.0_to_2.0.0.py". This script takes your current input configuration from inputs.conf and updates it to a newer modular version (while leaving a backup). Along with updating inputs.conf, this script creates ta_netapp_eseries_account.conf with details about the SANtricity Web Services Proxy instances previously used to manage monitored arrays. These details appear in the "Configuration" page of the Add-on. The password field of each "account" (SANtricity Web Services Proxy instance) comes up empty for security reasons and all inputs come up disabled. Navigate to the "Configuration" page of the Add-on and edit each "account" by adding a password. Once, passwords for all "accounts" have been added, either enable all "inputs" manually or run the second script by executing "$SPLUNK_HOME$/bin/splunk cmd python upgrade_helper_from_1.0.0_to_2.0.0.py". Restart Splunk to complete setup.
<p/>
    </html>
    </panel>
    <panel>
      <title>Compatibility Matrix</title>
      <table>
        <search>
          <query>| inputlookup nesa_compatibility_matrix | eval MainAppVersion=replace(MainAppVersion,"\|",",") | eval WebProxyVersion=replace(WebProxyVersion,"\|",",")  | eval ControllerFirmwareVersion=replace(ControllerFirmwareVersion,"\|",",") | table TAVersion MainAppVersion WebProxyVersion ControllerFirmwareVersion | rename MainAppVersion as "Main App Versions" TAVersion as "Technology Add-on Version" WebProxyVersion as "Web Service Proxy Version" ControllerFirmwareVersion as "Controller Firmware Version"</query>
          <sampleRatio>1</sampleRatio>
        </search>
        <option name="count">10</option>
        <option name="dataOverlayMode">none</option>
        <option name="drilldown">none</option>
        <option name="percentagesRow">false</option>
        <option name="rowNumbers">false</option>
        <option name="totalsRow">false</option>
        <option name="wrap">true</option>
      </table>
      <html>
      <p/>
      Controller firmware versions given above apply to compatibility with Splunk plugin features ONLY. See the NetApp interoperability Matrix for information on the minimum Web Services Proxy version required to monitor the controllers in your deployment.
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>