<dashboard stylesheet="xsv.css">
  <label>Command Reference</label>
  <row>
    <html>
    <p><span
          class="head2">Extreme Search Commands</span></p>
      <p>
        All Extreme Search functions may be entered as commands directly within Splunk Search.  Commands are executed, where possible, in parallel on the search peers. Results are returned in the same way all other Splunk Search results are returned. It is not necessary to use an external interface.  Extreme Search for Splunk includes the commands listed below. Click on any command name to view the help page for that command. 
      </p>

      <table width="100%" class="table table-striped table-responsive">
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th width="200" class="head5">COMMAND</th>
            <th width="150" class="head5">CATEGORY</th>
            <th width="400" class="head5">DESCRIPTION</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsAggregateAutoRegression">xsAggregateAutoRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Combines multiple Auto Regression algorithms in a weighted fashion to produce a new aggregate regression formula.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsAggregateCorrelation">xsAggregateCorrelation</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Combines multiple correlation algorithms in a weighted fashion to produce a new aggregate correlation formula.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsAggregateLinearRegression">xsAggregateLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Combines multiple Linear Regression algorithms in a weighted fashion to produce a new aggregate regression formula.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsAggregateNonLinearRegression">xsAggregateNonLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Combines multiple NonLinear Regression algorithms in a weighted fashion to produce a new aggregate regression formula.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsAggregateSpearmanCorrelation">xsAggregateSpearmanCorrelation</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Combines multiple Spearman Correlation algorithms in a weighted fashion to produce a new aggregate Spearman Correlation formula.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsApplyAutoRegression">xsApplyAutoRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Applies a formula created via xsPerformAutoRegression (or xsAggreateAutoRegression) against a stream of data.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsApplyLinearRegression">xsApplyLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Applies a formula created via xsPerformLinearRegression (or xsAggregateLinearRegression) against a stream of data.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsApplyNonLinearRegression">xsApplyNonLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Applies a formula created via xsPerformNonLinearRegression (or xsAggreateNonLinearRegression) against a stream of data.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCloneContext">xsCloneContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Makes a full copy of a Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCloneConcept">xsCloneConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Copies a Concept from one Context to another.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCreateConcept">xsCreateConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates a Concept for an existing Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCreateDDContext">xsCreateDDContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates a data driven context, which contains concepts based on a variety of methods of mapping qualitative semantics to the data. Note: This is a Splunk 'streaming' command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCreateUDContext">xsCreateUDContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates a user defined context, which contains concepts based on a variety of methods of mapping qualitative semantics to the data. This is a Splunk 'generating' command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDeleteContext">xsDeleteContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Deletes a Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDeleteConcept">xsDeleteConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Deletes a Concept from a Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDiscoverTrend">xsDiscoverTrend</a> </td>
            <td>Predictive Analytics</td>
            <td>Takes the lowest and highest x value, applies linear regression to these values, and maps the results to the Concept represented by the Y field.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDisplayContext">xsDisplayContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Displays all of the Concepts in a Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDisplayConcept">xsDisplayConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Displays one or more Concepts (with hedges).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsDisplayWhere">xsDisplayWhere</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Displays the (hedged) Concepts used by xsWhere.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsFindBestConcept">xsFindBestConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Returns the name of the Concept that best fits (highest compatibility) the field, as well as the associated compatibility index (CIX).  </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsFindMembership">xsFindMembership</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Returns the membership value of a data value in each concept in a specified context, or returns the data value given a membership value in a specified context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsGetCompatibility">xsGetCompatibility</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Determine the compatibility index for the field in each concept in a context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsGetContextFields">xsGetContextFields</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Displays the specified fields of a context as a table.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsGetDistance">xsGetDistance</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Determine the distance (in miles) between two locations.</td>
          -</tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsGetWhereCIX">xsGetWhereCIX</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Generates the compatibility index (cix) of a conceptual query.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsListContexts">xsListContexts</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>List the contexts in private, app or global.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsListConcepts">xsListConcepts</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>List the concepts from a context in private, app or global.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsListUOM">xsListUOM</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>List the Unit of Measurement (UOM) from a context in private, app or global.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsMergeContexts">xsMergeContexts</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Merge two contexts into a new context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsNormalize">xsNormalize</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td> For each event, lookup the value of a field and calculate the normalized value as a percentage between the domainMin and the domainMax of a context. Used to normalize data across multiple Contexts. Very useful in risk scoring.</td>
          </tr>
          <!--
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsOverlayContext">xsOverlayContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Overlays multiple contexts on a chart or in a table</td>
          </tr>
          -->
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPerformAutoRegression">xsPerformAutoRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Performs linear (least squares) and polynomial (max entropy) regression for a set of data streams. For linear regression, the function y=coef1*x+coef2 is generated for each stream. For polynomial, a three coefficient function, y= coef0*x^2+coef1*x+coef2, is generated for each stream.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPerformCorrelation">xsPerformCorrelation</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Performs correlation of a data stream or compatibility index stream.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPerformLinearRegression">xsPerformLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Performs linear regression of data streams (x) over other data streams(y). For each pair of data streams, the following function is generated: y=slope*x+intercept</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPerformNonLinearRegression">xsPerformNonLinearRegression</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Performs quadratic (non-linear) regression of data streams (x) over other data streams (y). For each pair of data streams, the following function is generated: y=coef0*x^2+coef1*x+coef2.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPerformSpearmanCorrelation">xsPerformSpearmanCorrelation</a> </td>
            <td>Statistical Reasoning</td>
            <td>Performs Spearman correlation of a data stream or compatibility index stream.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsPredict">xsPredict</a> </td>
            <td>Predictive Analytics</td>
            <td>Predicts the future values of a time-series data stream.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsRenameConcept">xsRenameConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Renames a Concept.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsRenameContext">xsRenameContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Renames a Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsSetContextFields">xsSetContextFields</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Sets the value(s) of the specified field(s) of a context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsUpdateConcept">xsUpdateConcept</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Updates an existing Concept in an existing Context.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsUpdateDDContext">xsUpdateDDContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Updates a data-driven context, which contains concepts based on a variety of methods of mapping qualitative semantics to the data. Note: This is a Splunk 'streaming' command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsUpdateUDContext">xsUpdateUDContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Updates a user-defined context, which contains concepts based on a variety of methods of mapping qualitative semantics to the data. This is a Splunk 'generating' command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsWhere">xsWhere</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Selects a collection of rows from the data space based on the application of qualitative semantics (which are created by xsCreateDDContext or xsCreateUDContext).</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <br /><br />
       <p><span
          class="head2">Extreme Search Macros</span></p>
      <p>
        Extreme Search includes a number of powerful macros to help you to more easily leverage qualitative expression in Splunk. 
      </p>

           <table width="100%" class="table table-striped table-responsive">
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th width="200" class="head5">MACRO</th>
            <th width="150" class="head5">CATEGORY</th>
            <th width="400" class="head5">DESCRIPTION</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="auto_update_context">auto_update_context(5)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Uses the value of the &quot;search&quot; field in a context to automatically update the context.</td>
          </tr>
                                 <tr>
            <td> <a href="by_token">by_token(0..1)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Builds a "by classlist" token if the classlist is not null. Otherwise returns "".</td>
          </tr>
                    <tr>
            <td> <a href="context_stats">context_stats(2)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Generates the statistics needed for creation of a data driven context.</td>
          </tr>
                              <tr>
            <td> <a href="create_context">create_context(2..6)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates a data driven context with a variable set of arguments.</td>
          </tr>
                    <tr>
            <td> <a href="discover_trend">discover_trend(3)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Discovers the trend for "fieldY" over "fieldX".</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td height="20"> <a href="find_best_concept">find_best_concept(3)</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Returns the name of the Concept that best fits (highest compatibility) the field, as well as the associated compatibility index (CIX).</td>
            </tr>
		</tbody>
      </table>
      <br /><br />
            <p><span
          class="head2">Extreme Search Visualization Commands</span></p>
      <p>
        The following commands are provided by the Extreme Search Visualization app. Like commands provided by Extreme Search, they may be entered as commands directly within Splunk Search.  Results are returned within the Splunk web interface. It is not necessary to use an external interface.   Click on any command name to view the help page for that command. 
      </p>

      <table width="100%" class="table table-striped table-responsive">
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th width="200" class="head5">COMMAND</th>
            <th width="150" class="head5">CATEGORY</th>
            <th width="400" class="head5">DESCRIPTION</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCreateADContext">xsCreateADContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates an Anomaly driven Context containing two Concepts which typically represent Normal and Anomalous. Note: This is a Splunk 'streaming' command.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsCreateCDContext">xsCreateCDContext</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td><p>Creates a Crossover driven context,  which contains Concepts based on a variety of methods of mapping qualitative semantics to the data. Note: This is a Splunk 'streaming' command.</p></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsvCreateSavedSearch">xsvCreateSavedSearch</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Creates a Saved Search in a named app.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsvExploreContexts">xsvExploreContexts</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Discovers  Contexts in the Splunk environment.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsvListSearches">xsvListSearches</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Discovers all searches in the Splunk environment, which contain Extreme Search commands.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td> <a href="xsvUpdateConceptShape">xsvUpdateConceptShape</a> </td>
            <td>Conceptual Search</td>
            <td>Redefines the shape of a Concept in a Context and all its classes.</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <br /><br />
<p align="center">
  <span class="head5">Scianta Extreme Search Visualization for Splunk is part of the Scianta Analytics Cognitive
  Computing Suite</span>
        <br />
        <a href="http://www.scianta.com/"
          target="_blank">
          <img alt="Scianta Analytics" src="/static/app/xsv/images/Scianta_Analytics_150.png" />
        </a>
</p><br />
      <p>VERSION: 20150817.2<br />
      Custom application development for Splunk by <a href="http://www.concanon.com/#services"
          target="_blank"> Concanon LLC.</a><br />
	Some portions of Extreme Search for Splunk are patented under US Patent 9,087,090.<br />
Copyright 2015 Scianta Analytics LLC. All Rights Reserved.</p>

    </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>
