<dashboard stylesheet="xsv.css">
  <label>Intro to Conceptual Search</label>
  <row>
    <html>
        <span
          class="head2">An Introduction to Conceptual Search</span>
      <p></p><p>
        <span
          class="head3">Concepts and Contexts</span>
      </p>
      <p>As humans, we tend to think conceptually. A concept can be characterized by a semantic term
        that represents it. Terms such as Tall, Short, Long, Early, Late, Fast, and Slow are
        meaningful to us because they represent concepts that we understand based on our historical
        experience. Let's think for a moment about the concept of <strong>tall</strong> as it
        relates to people. We share a common notion of what <strong>tall</strong>  means, based upon
        our shared experience. If someone tells us a person is <strong>tall</strong>, we have a good
        understanding of what that means. </p>
      <p>Let's consider some examples:</p> 
      Is Kareem Abdul-Jabbar <strong>tall</strong>? Certainly. Do
      you know exactly what his height is, in inches? Probably not, but we can all agree that he's
        <strong>tall</strong>.<br /> 
        Was Napoleon <strong>tall</strong>? No. In fact, he's become an
      icon for an alternate concept: <strong>short</strong>.<br /> 
      Actor Brad Garrett? He's quite
        <strong>tall</strong>.
      <br />Tom Cruise? By most measures, he is not <strong>tall</strong>.<br /> Osama bin Laden?
      People agree that he was very <strong>tall</strong>.<br />
      <p>Tall is not defined by some threshold parameter. Is someone who stands 6'8&quot; considered
        tall? Sure. How 'bout someone 5'11&quot;? Also tall. And 5'10&quot;? We'd probably agree
        that yes, 5'10&quot; is still considered tall. It may be less tall than Kareem, but still
        tall.</p>
      <p> The takeaway? There is no threshold parameter that determines <strong>tall</strong> vs not
          <strong>tall</strong>. <strong>Tall</strong> is a <strong>Concept</strong>, not a
        threshold value. This turns out to true of most all concepts, from characterizations of
        height to network latency to sales performance to musical talent to public sentiment.</p>
<p>
<p><span class="xsv-inset">In the underlying cognitive computing engine that drives
    Extreme Search, each <strong>Semantic Term</strong> or <strong>Concept</strong> is characterized by a mathematical <strong>Fuzzy
      Set</strong>. Such a set consists of an array of groups of two numbers: the value of the field in question and the membership of that value in the <strong>Concept</strong>. </span></p>
        <br />
        In fact, we can graph a mathematical representation of the <strong>Concept</strong> of<em> tall</em>. The graph in <strong>Figure 1</strong> might be one definition of <em>tall</em>. Note that the X axis is Height, in inches, ranging from 48 inches
        to 84 inches, a fair guess at the range of heights we'd see in a large sample of people. The
        Y axis depicts the degree of membership in this <strong>Concept</strong>  of<em> tall</em>. In our depiction, a person who stands 60&quot; has zero membership
        in the concept  of<em> tall</em>. Someone 84&quot; has a membership of 1, or 100%. In
        this scenario, an 84&quot; person is &quot;more tall&quot; than a 72&quot; person. If we
        were looking at the underlying fuzzy mathematics that represent our concept  of<em> tall</em>, we'd say that 84&quot; has 100% membership in the set<em> tall</em>, while 72&quot; has a bit under 50%.</p><br /><br />
        <p
        align="center"><img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/tall_set_600.png"
          width="600"
          height="330"
          alt="tall" /><br /> Figure 1</p><br />
      <p
        align="left"> A question arises here. Most people would agree that, among a large sample of
        people, we think of 72&quot; as quite tall. The notion that 72&quot; has less than 50%
        membership in our <strong>Concept</strong> of<em> tall</em> doesn't seem quite right. That's OK. This
        just means that the straight-line function we drew to represent our concept of <strong>tall</strong> is probably not a very accurate representation of the concept. We
        can fix that. The graph in <strong>Figure 2</strong> is another definition of our <strong>Concept</strong> of<em> tall</em>. This one probably comes closer to an accurate representation of
        what we think of, when we think of<em> tall</em>.</p><br />
      <p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/tall_set_s_600.png"
          width="600"
          height="330" /><br /> Figure 2</p><br />
      <p><br />
        <span
          class="head3">Capturing Points of View: Contexts</span>
      </p>
      <p>When we're thinking about an idea like the <em>height</em> of people, we consider a
        number of related <strong>Concepts</strong>. The <strong>Concepts</strong>
        <em>tall</em> and <em>short</em> are two "conceptually coherent" terms that
        describe <strong>Concepts</strong> relating to <em>height</em>. In Extreme Search, we call this  coherent
        grouping of <strong>Concepts</strong> a <strong>Context</strong>. A <strong>Context</strong> characterizes a
        particular view of the world based upon the meaning of the terms that define it. Such a <strong>Context</strong> can be seen in <strong>Figure 3</strong>.</p><br />
      <p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/height-s_600.png"
          width="600"
          height="330" /><br /> Figure 3 </p><br />
      <p>The <strong>Context</strong>
        <em>height</em> in <strong>Figure 3</strong> illustrates an important characteristic of <strong>Terms</strong> within a <strong>Context</strong>: that is, that terms or <strong>Concepts</strong> often overlap. It is very possible for a value under analysis to have membership in more
        than one <strong> Concept</strong>. In our example here, a person can be somewhat tall and
        somewhat short at the same time. This idea is true of most any <strong>Context</strong>
        applying to most any knowledge domain. It embodies the way we, as humans, think of the world
        and it is an extraordinarily powerful tenet of cognitive computing.</p>
      <br />
      <p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/height_demo_600.png"
          width="600"
          height="330" /><br /> Figure 4 </p><br />
      <p><strong>Figure 4</strong> illustrates another definition of the <strong>Context</strong>
        <em>height</em>. This illustration is the display of a <strong>Context</strong> called
          <em>height</em> which we've defined in Extreme Search for Splunk. Note that this
          <strong>Context</strong> is comprised of five 
        <tstrong>terms</tstrong>: <em>tiny, short,
        typical, tall</em> and <em>gigantic</em>. There's nothing particularly special about these five names.
        They simply have meaning to the author when describing the notion of <em>height</em>.
        They're defined by the user and represent that user's perspective with regard to the height
        of people.</p>
      <p>In Extreme Search, we allow users to define <strong>Context</strong>s either with or without regard to a
        particular data set. These <strong>Context</strong>s are saved in Extreme Search and can be used to analyze
        subsequent data sets or the same data set in a various time ranges. A subject matter expert
        might define a <strong>Context</strong> with which the staff of his company should analyze a particular
        knowledge domain. For example, a network expert might define a <strong>Context</strong>
        called <em>latency</em> that support is personnel or a monitoring system would use when
        analyzing real time network performance. If the <strong>Context</strong> was generated using
        baseline data, applying it in real time analysis would immediately identify anomalies,
        without the need to learn baseline behavior. Scianta's concept-based cognitive computing
        engine can quickly model baseline behavior without the need for more conventional
        parametric machine learning.</p>
      <p><em>So this is pretty interesting. What does it get us?</em></p>
      <p><strong>Concepts</strong> and collections of them which we call
          <strong>Contexts</strong> are critical components in concept-based cognitive computing.
        They facilitate the ability to gain deep insight from your data by asking  
          <em>qualitative</em>, rather than <em>quantitative</em> questions, and to ask those
        questions in natural language.</p><br />
      <span
        class="head3">Conceptual Coherence</span>
      <p>In our example of the linear (<strong>Figure 1</strong>) vs. S-shaped (<strong>Figure 2</strong>) definitions of the term <em>tall</em>, we noted that the shape of the membership function for a
          <strong>term</strong> is significant. In fact, it is very important that the shape of the
          <strong>term</strong> represent the linguistic meaning of the <strong>term</strong>. When
        we say <strong>tall</strong>, the set of values that have membership in that
          <strong>concept</strong> should make linguistic sense. In the same way that someone would
        be confused if you called Kareem Abdul-Jabbar <strong>short</strong> and Napoleon
          <strong>tall</strong>, they can be confused if we define concepts in Extreme Search
        that don't make linguistic sense. It is also important that all  <strong>terms</strong>
        defined in a <strong>Context</strong> be conceptually coherent – that they share the same
        "universe of discourse". It would be confusing if one <strong>term</strong> dealt with
          <em>Time</em> and another dealt with <em>Distance</em>.</p>
      <br />
      <p><span
        class="head3">To Infinity... and Beyond</span></p>
      <p>In our <em>height</em> example, above, we used a range of values for <em>height</em> from 48 inches to 84 inches. We assume that the range of 48 inches to 84 inches was our "universe of discourse" –  that is, the range of all possible values of <em>height</em> that we care about in our <strong>Context</strong> <em>height</em>. This may or may not be a valid assumption. What happens if we're suddenly faced with a value of 40 inches or 100 inches? What happens if our "universe of discourse" expands? It turns out that this happens often, and Extreme Search is designed to handle such a condition seamlessly. That's why the <strong>Concepts</strong> at either end of a <strong>Context</strong> are typically S-shaped. In Extreme Search, all <strong>Contexts</strong> extend infinitely in either direction along X and all <strong>Concepts</strong> are analyzed using the membership values they held at the end of the original "universe of discourse". A value of X that is below the <strong>Context's</strong> "universe of discourse" is assumed to have a membership of 1 in the low <strong>Concept</strong> (<em>tiny</em> in this case). So a value of 40 inches has a membership of 1 in <em>tiny</em>. Similarly, a value of X that is above the <strong>Context's</strong> "universe of discourse" is assumed to have a membership of 1 in the high <strong>Concept</strong>, <em>gigantic</em>. Likewise, a value of 40 inches continues to have the same membership (0) in other <strong>Concepts</strong> (<em>short, typical, tall</em> and <em>gigantic</em>) that those <strong>Concepts</strong> held at the end of the <strong>Context</strong>.  <strong> Figure 5</strong> illustrates this using our <strong>Context</strong> for <em>height</em>.</p>
      <br />
            <p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/height_demo_ext_860.png"
          width="860"
          height="330" /><br /> Figure 5 </p><br />
      
<p><span
        class="head3">Increasing Granularity: Context Classes</span></p>
      <p>As we've learned, a collection of <strong>Concepts</strong> applied to a specific knowledge domain is called a <strong>Context</strong>. The notion of <em>tall</em> has a very different scale when applied in the context of the <em>height</em> of buildings than it does in the context of the <em>height</em> of people. This idea of <strong>Context</strong> allows us to explore the world in a very granular way. Extreme Search supports high granularity of the context in which knowledge is applied through a mechanism called <strong>Context Class</strong>. </p>
      <p>Let's take another look at the familiar idea of <em>height</em> as it applies to people. In the <strong>Context</strong> <em>height</em>, we decided above to divide <em>height</em> into five <strong>Concepts</strong>: <em>tiny, short,
      typical, tall and gigantic</em>. That allowed us to classify people by <em>height</em> in a way that's intuitive and well understood by most observers. If I say &quot;Show me the people who are   tall&quot;, you and I have a shared understanding of what that means. It turns out that there may be other classifications of people that might affect our notion of <em>height</em>. An obvious one is gender. The fact is, on balance, women tend to be &quot;less tall&quot; than men. That is, in a similar sized sampling of men and women, the distribution of the values of <em>height</em> tend to skew lower in women and higher in men. In numerical terms, the concept <em>tall</em> for men is different than the concept of <em>tall</em> for women. Another interesting classification might be occupation. The <strong>Concept</strong> of <em>tall</em> for basketball players is probably different than the <strong>Concept</strong> of <em>tall</em> for jockeys. </p>
      <p>In Extreme Search we allow for this kind of granularity by allowing <strong>Context</strong>s to be classified by a secondary data field. In this case, gender. We might have a default class of <em>height</em> that is applied without regard to gender, as well as classes of <em>height</em> which are determined by a data field called <em>gender</em>. If we scale our <em>height</em> <strong>Context</strong> by looking at all people (the <em>default</em> class), males (the <em>male</em> class) and females (the <em>female</em> class), we're able to classify our data qualitatively, with meaningful granularity.</p>
      <p><strong>Context Classes</strong> can be used to obtain important granularity in most any knowledge domain. A sales_revenue <strong>Context</strong> might be classified by a product_type field or a sales_region field, so the <strong>Concept</strong>  of <em>typical</em> sales_revenue accurately reflects the product type or sales region. It might be meaningful to classify the count of failed_logins  by user_role or host_type or hour_of_day. The risk scoring of a host might be classified by facility or zone or region.</p>
      <p>The Splunk App for Enterprise Security makes good use of <strong>Context Classes</strong>. You can investigate this using the <a href="/app/xsv/xsv_explore_context">Context Explorer</a> dashboard in the Extreme Search Visualization app.</p>
      <p>
        <br />
        <span
        class="head3">Embracing Nuance: Hedges</span>
      </p>
      <p><bold>Concepts</bold> and <strong>Contexts</strong> are the basis of Conceptual
        Search but they don't, on their own, support a very nuanced view of the world. A true
        Cognitive Computing system, a system designed to "think" like we do, needs to understand
        nuance.</p>
      <p>Scianta Extreme Search for Splunk employs the notion of "hedges" to capture nuanced
        variation to concepts. Hedges are linguistic modifiers, adjectives, that modify the
        meaning of a concept. To learn more about <strong>hedges</strong> and other methods
        employed by Extreme Search to embrace the nuance of human thought, click on Learn More About Hedges.</p>
      <a class="btn btn-xtreme" href="hedges"> <span class="icon-play"></span> Learn More About Hedges </a> 
<p></p><br />
      <p align="center">
        <span class="head5">Scianta Extreme Search Visualization for Splunk is part of the Scianta Analytics Cognitive
          Computing Suite</span>
        <br />
        <a href="http://www.scianta.com/"
          target="_blank">
          <img alt="Scianta Analytics" src="/static/app/xsv/images/Scianta_Analytics_150.png" />
        </a>
      </p>
      <br />
      <p>VERSION: 20150823.6<br />
      Custom application development for Splunk by <a href="http://www.concanon.com/#services"
          target="_blank"> Concanon LLC.</a><br />
	Some portions of Extreme Search for Splunk are patented under US Patent 9,087,090.<br />
Copyright 2015 Scianta Analytics LLC. All Rights Reserved.</p>
    </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>
