<dashboard stylesheet="xsv.css">
<label>Support</label>
<row>
<html>
<div> <img src="/static/app/xsv/images/Scianta_Analytics_150.png" style="display:inline-block;"/></div>
<br />
<p> <span class="head3">Support Overview</span> </p>
<p>Extreme Search Visualization (XSV), is  a "helper" app for  Extreme Search for Splunk, which ships as part of the Splunk App for Enterprise Security. Extreme Search itself is now owned and supported by Splunk Inc. You can learn more about Splunk's many support options by clicking on &quot;Learn About Splunk Support&quot;.</p>
<p> <a class="btn btn-xtreme" href="http://www.splunk.com/en_us/support-and-services.html" target="_blank"> <span class="icon-play"></span> Learn About Splunk Support</a><br /> <br /><br />
</p>
<p><span class="head3">Support for XS Visualization</span></p>
<p>The XS Visualization for Splunk app is a part of the Scianta Analytics cognitive computing suite from Scianta Analytics LLC. It is not a Splunk Inc. product and is not supported by Splunk Support. If you have any questions about the operation of XSV, please feel free to contact us. We're here to help!</p>
<p> <a class="btn btn-xtreme" href="http://www.scianta.com/support" target="_blank"> <span class="icon-play"></span> Contact the Scianta Support Team</a><br /><br /><br />
</p>
<p><span class="head3">Questions About Leading Edge Analytics in Splunk?</span></p>
<p>XSV was developed by the professional Splunk consultants at Concanon using cognitive computing technology from Scianta Analytics. If you have a tough use case in Business Analytics, Security Analytics, Fraud Detection or IT Operations, we encourage you to give Concanon a call. Concanon has unmatched expertise delivering powerful solutions on the Splunk platform.</p><br />
<p> <a class="btn btn-xtreme" href="http://www.concanon.com" target="_blank"> <span class="icon-play"></span> Contact the Concanon Solutions Team</a> </p><br /><br /><br />
<p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/concanon_insight_logo_b_240.png" /><br /> </p><br /><br /><br />
<p>VERSION: 20150823.2<br />
      Custom application development for Splunk by <a href="http://www.concanon.com/#services"
          target="_blank"> Concanon LLC.</a><br />
	Some portions of Extreme Search for Splunk are patented under US Patent 9,087,090.<br />
Copyright 2015 Scianta Analytics LLC. All Rights Reserved.</p>
</html>
</row>
</dashboard>
