<dashboard stylesheet="xsv.css">
<label>Using XS Visualization</label>
<row>
<html>
<div> <img src="/static/app/xsv/images/Scianta_Analytics_150.png" style="display:inline-block;"/>
  <h2 style="display:inline-block;padding-left:20px;color:#0069C2;font-size:20px;font-weight:bold;">Using Extreme Search Visualization</h2>
</div>
<br />
<p> <span class="head2">Introduction</span> </p>
<p>Extreme Search Visualization (XSV), is designed as a "helper" app for Scianta Analytics' Extreme Search for Splunk. Extreme Search for Splunk adds powerful Conceptual Search, Statistical Reasoning and Predictive Analysis functions to the Splunk search language. You can learn more about Scianta Analytics' Extreme Search for Splunk on the <a href="xsv_overview">Overview page</a>. XSV provides a great deal of documentation to assist you in leveraging the power of Extreme Search both in the Splunk App for Enterprise Security and in other applications in Splunk. XSV also provides a set of dashboards and wizards to help you explore, manage and visualizes Extreme Search knowledge objects.</p><br /> 
<p><span class="head2">Conceptual Search</span></p>
<p>The primary focus of Extreme Search and, by extensions, the Extreme Search Visualization app, is Conceptual Search. Conceptual Search allows any user to gain insight from Splunk data using Qualitative Expressions. Rather than having to craft searches using brittle, arcane quantitative parameters, Extreme Search allows you to build queries based on the concepts you're interested in, and to state those queries in natural language. You can learn more about Conceptual Search and Qualitative Expression on the <a href="concept_intro">Introduction to Conceptual Search page</a>.</p><br /> 

<p><span class="head2">The XSV Home Page</span></p>
<p>When you launch the Extreme Search Visualization app, you'll be directed to the XSV Home page. This page serves as the central navigational page for XSV.  We'll use it here as a central reference when describing the app and how to use it. You'll note that the page is divided into two sections: Explore and Visualize, and Create and Modify.</p>
<p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/xsv_home.png"
          width="600"
          height="405" /><br /> 
Figure 1<br />
XSV Home Page</p><br />
<p><span class="head2">Explore and Visualize</span></p>
<p>The Explore and Visualize dashboards in XSV are designed to assist you in exploring and visualizing the Conceptual Search knowledge objects in Extreme Search. Of these dashboards, the Context Explorer is the most powerful.</p>
<p><span class="head4">Context Explorer</span></p>
<p>The Context Explorer gives you an overview of all Extreme Search knowledge objects in your Splunk environment. The Context Explorer presents a graphical view of the Extreme Search architectural hierarchy. (Learn more about the Extreme Search architectural hierarchy on the <a href="xsv_overview">Overview page</a>.) The Context Explorer may take a few moments to return information. It catalogs every app in your Splunk environment as well as any Extreme Search knowledge objects each app may contain. [Note: The session handling behavior of the current version of Splunk Enterprise may cause the Context Explorer view to hang if you have more than one Splunk Web session open in your browser. If this occurs, please close the other session(s) and refresh the Context Explorer view.] </p><br />

<p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/context_explorer_2.png"
          width="600"
          height="405" /><br /> 
Figure 2<br />
Context Explorer</p><br />
<p>Navigate Extreme Search knowledge objects beginning with the App layer. All Apps in your Splunk environment that contain Extreme Search knowledge objects will be listed here. Scroll through Apps by clicking on the left and right scroll arrows. Click on any App to select it. With an App selected, the Context Navigator will display Containers, Contexts, Context Classes and Concepts contained in that App. Note that you may select &quot;Create Context&quot; in the Action menu for Apps to create a new Context in the Selected App.</p>
<p>With an App selected, you may scroll left and right through Context Containers contained in that App.  Click on a Container to select it. The Container Action menu gives you the option of creating a new Context within the selected Container. With a Container selected, the Context Explorer will display Contexts, Context Classes and Concepts contained by that Container. You may scroll left and right through Contexts contained by the selected Container. Click a Context to select it.</p>
<p>With a Context selected, you may scroll left and right through Classes of that Context. The Context Action menu allows you to initiate a number of actions on the Context.</p>

<p
        align="center">
<img
          src="/static/app/xsv/images/context_action.png"
          width="500"
          height="67" /><br /> 
Figure 3<br />
Context Action Menu</p>
<p><strong>Available actions include:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Clone a Context</li>
  <li>Create a Context (in the selected Container)</li>
  <li>Overlay Data on a Context</li>
  <li>Redefine a Context</li>
  <li>Use the Context in the XSV Search Manager</li>
</ul>
<p><br />
  <br />
</p>
<p><span class="head2">Learn</span></p>
<p><img src="/static/app/xsv/images/learn.png" width="106" height="77" align="left" alt="" style="PADDING-RIGHT: 20px"/>
Note the &quot;Learn&quot; icon in the upper righthand corner of the home page. Clicking this icon will take you to the Learning Center on the Scianta Analytics web site. The Learning Center contains the most recent versions of Extreme Search and XSV documentation, as well as additional documentation and white papers to allow you to dig deeper into Scianta Analytics cognitive computing technology. The &quot;Documentation&quot; menu in the XSV app also has a <a href="http://www.scianta.com/learn" target="_blank">Scianta Analytics Learning Center</a> selection.</p><br />
<p><span class="head4"></span></p>
<br />


<p>VERSION: 20150816.3<br />
      Custom application development for Splunk by <a href="http://www.concanon.com/#services"
          target="_blank"> Concanon LLC.</a><br />
	Some portions of Extreme Search for Splunk are patented under US Patent 9,087,090.<br />
Copyright 2015 Scianta Analytics LLC. All Rights Reserved.</p>
</html>
</row>
</dashboard>
