<dashboard>
<label>Preparing your Windows Server</label>

<row>
<html>
<h1>Welcome to the Splunk Modular Input for Microsoft Message Queuing</h1>

<p>Thank you for downloading the Splunk Modular Input for MSMQ.  We hope you will find it
useful to you.  Please note that this modular input requires specific configuration on 
your Windows server prior to using this modular input.  In addition, the modular input needs
to know about the format of the messages that are being received, through the provision of
a .NET assembly that formats the messages for output.</p>

<h1>Tested Platforms</h1>

<p>You can run the Splunk Modular Input for MSMQ on the following platforms:</p>

<ul>
<li>64-bit Windows Server 2008 R2</li>
<li>64-bit Windows Server 2012</li>
</ul>

<p>Other platforms may work, but they have not been tested.</p>

<h1>Preparing your server for the Splunk Modular Input for MSMQ</h1>

<p>Prior to installing the Splunk Modular Input for MSMQ, please ensure that the 
.NET Framework 4.5 and MSMQ Services are installed.  These are covered in more
detail below.</p>

<h2>Installing the .NET Framework 4.5</h2>

<p>If you are running Windows Server 2012, then it is likely that the .NET
Framework 4.5 is already installed.  If you are running Windows Server 2008 R2, 
you can download the .NET Framework 4.5 from the following location:</p>

<p style="margin-left: 16px;"><code>
<a href="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=268529" target="_blank">http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=268529</a>
</code></p>

<p>Note that the installer will often require that the system be rebooted.  If
this is a concern, ensure the installation is done during a maintenance window.</p>

<h2>Installing MSMQ</h2>

<p>Windows Server comes with the MSMQ Server as a Windows Feature.  The list of
features you need are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Message Queuing Server</li>
<li>MSMQ Directory Service Integration</li>
</ul>

<p>On Windows Server 2008 R2, go into Control Panel and Add/Remove Windows Features.
Select the features to install and walk through the resulting wizard to complete the
installation.</p>

<p>On Windows Server 2012, open the PowerShell console and type the following:</p>

<p><code><pre style="padding-left: 16px;">Import-Module ServerManager
Add-WindowsFeature MSMQ
Add-WindowsFeature MSMQ-Services
Add-WindowsFeature MSMQ-Server
Add-WindowsFeature MSMQ-Directory</pre></code></p>

<p>The addition of the MSMQ server should not require a reboot of the server.</p>
</html>
</row>
	
</dashboard>