<dashboard>
<label>Custom Message Handlers</label>

<row>
<html>
<h1>About Message Handlers</h1>
<p>MSMQ is a queuing system for message passing systems.  It allows messages to be passed from 
one sub-system to another, even if they are on remote servers.  A message can be as simple as
a text string or as complex as a serialized binary .NET object.  Since there is no method of
knowing in advance in what format the messages are going to be sent, we require a message
handler to decode the contents of each message.  The message handler is a .NET Assembly that
is placed in the bin\MessageHandlers directory of the SA-ModularInput-MSMQ app.  Once integrated, 
the class of the message handler is provided during the input definition.</p>

<h1>Developing a Custom Message Handler</h1>

<p>To assist in your development efforts, a complete example has been provided as a Visual Studio 
2012 solution on GitHub.  This solution can be cloned from 
<a href="https://github.com/nczeczulin/splunk-mi-msmq-example-handler" target="_blank">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>Once you have your completed assembly, copy the DLL into the SA-ModularInput-MSMQ\bin\MessageHandlers directory.</p>

<h2>Project References</h2>

<p>To process the messages, the custom message handler must add the following References:</p>

<ul style="padding-left: 16px;">
<li>System.Messaging</li>
<li>System.ComponentModel.Composition</li>
<li>Splunk.ModularInput.Msmq.MessageHandlerContracts</li>
</ul>

<p>The DLL for the Splunk-specific reference can be obtained in the SA-ModularInput-MSMQ\bin directory
of the app.</p>

<h2>Implementing the Message Handler Interface</h2>

<p>To implement a message handler, the following interface must be implemented:</p>

<div id="msmq-handler-interface"></div>

<h2>Reference Implementation</h2>

<div id="msmq-handler-reference"><p>To see a reference implementation or the message handler, please see our <a href="https://gist.github.com/6129089">GIST</a> on GitHub, 
or the Visual Studio 2012 solution mentioned at the top of the page.</p></div>

</html>
</row>

</dashboard>