<dashboard isVisible="false">
	<label>Web Development</label>
	<row>
        <html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/maps_landing"><h2 align="left">Previous: Maps</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/forwarder_landing"><h2 align="right">Next: Forwarder Management</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
    </row>
        <row>
        <html>
		<p>The Splunk Application Framework expands the capabilities of dashboards. The new framework includes both Web and Application Framework. The Web Framework
		enables users to display events using HTML and JavaScript, while the Application Framework allows users to display events with third party data visualization
		libraries, such as D3 and JSChart. </p>
            <h1>Using the feature</h1>
            <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		<p>In Splunk 6 the application framework is embracing industry standard and open development technologies to accelerate the adoption of Splunk
		as a platform among the broad developer community and our enterprise customers. There are 2 main areas of the framework: the client side (JavaScript) and
		server side (Python).</p>
                <p><b>Escaping from SimpleXML to Framework JavaScript</b><br/>
                Splunk 6 significantly eases the migration path from rapid dashboarding in SimpleXML to more complex development via the framework.
		This is done by escaping simple xml to the javascript, client-side, aspects of the framework. There are UI capabilities that exist that
		will enable someone to escape from simple xml to the framework and have the full capabilities of the framework available to them to build applications that
		meet their needs.</p>
		<p><b>Client Side Development (JavaScript)</b><br/> 
                For the client side development, the framework makes it easier to incorporate existing custom or 3rd party visualization elements. The visualization
		elements based on the D3 <a href="http://d3js.org/" >library</a> show the most promise and have generated a lot of interest in the developer community.
		By working with the application framework, your imagination and the whole internet is at your disposal.</p>
                <p><b>Server Side (Python and Django)</b><br/>
                Additionally, there is a server-side component in the framework that allows developers to handle aspects of app development that are more appropriately handled
		at that tier in the architecture. For example, because we are leveraging django in the framework, we are taking advantage of a number of built-in facilities
		to ease the creation of application setup capabilities for Splunk apps. The server side aspects are also handling authentication behavior for applications. </p>
            </div>
	    <h1>Example</h1>
	    <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		<ul>
                    <li><a href="/app/splunk6overview/framework_simple_xml_escaped" >Simple Framework Example</a></li>
                    <li><a href="/app/splunk6overview/framework_simple_xml_escaped_and_modified">Escaped XML Example</a></li>
                </ul>
	    </div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/framework_creation.png" />
		</div>
        </html>
    </row>
	<row>
		<html>
			<h1>Resources</h1>
			<a href="/help?location=whatsnew.integratedwebframework" target="_blank"><h2>Learn More</h2></a>
			<a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0beta/ReleaseNotes/MeetSplunk" target="_blank"><h2>Intro to Splunk 6 documentation</h2></a>
		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
	
