<dashboard isVisible="true">
	<label>Welcome</label>
	<row>
		<html>
		<h1>Splunk 6 Enterprise Overview</h1>
		<p>Welcome to Splunk 6, the newest release of the leading operational intelligence platform used by over 6,000 organizations worldwide. This
		version delivers our fastest analytical platform to date, self-service operational intelligence, more intuitive user experience to increase
		productivity for all users, simplified management of enterprise-scale deployments, and richer developer environment for building custom
		Splunk apps.</p>
		<p>This application will guide you through the new features by providing examples, including sample reports and dashboards.  More information and
		details are available in our documentation for Splunk 6.</p>
		</html>
	</row>
	<row>
		<html>
<style type="text/css">

h1 {
   font-size:20px;
   line-height:20px;
   margin:2px;
}

h3 {
   font-size:16px;
   line-height: 16px;
   margin:2px;
}

</style>
<div></div>
<div id="Splunk6HomeLanding">
 <div class="Splunk6HomeContainer">
  <table class="Splunk6HomeTable">
   
   <tr>
	<td id="Splunk6intuitiveUXImage" class="SplunkImageCell">
		<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/splunk6intuitiveuxicon.png" alt="Intuitive UX"/>
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6intuitiveUX" class="Splunk6HomeCell">
		<h1>Intuitive User Interface</h1>
		<p>All new interface that increases productivity of individual users by optimizing access to
		specific apps and content</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/newhome_landing"><h3>Home Experience</h3></a>
		<p>Redesigned Home Page provides easy customization and access to application sub pages</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/newsearch_landing"><h3>Search Experience</h3></a>
		<p>Optimized access enables searching and analyzing of data from a single interface</p>
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6analyticsImage" class="SplunkImageCell">
		<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/splunk6analyticsIcon.png" alt="Analytics" />
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6Analytics" class="Splunk6HomeCell">
		<h1>Powerful Analytics</h1>
		<p>Analytical tools that anyone can use</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/datamodel_landing"><h3>Data Model</h3></a>
		<p>Make unstructured data more valuable by developing Data Models.  Data models are structured data sets that drive Pivot
		and can be created by administrators and power users</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/pivot_landing"><h3>Pivot</h3></a>
		<p>Explore, manipulate, and visualize Machine Data without using the search language</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/predictive_landing"><h3>Predictive Analytics</h3></a>
		<p>Find patterns in data to predict system capacity and resource utilization</p>

	</td>
   </tr>
    
   <tr>
	<td id="Splunk6DevelopersImage" class="SplunkImageCell">
		<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/splunk6developersIcon.png" alt="Developers" />
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6Developers" class="Splunk6HomeCell">
		<h1>Rich Developer Experience</h1>
		<p>Build interactive dashboards and user workflows using Simple XML and the integrated development framework</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/simple_dashboards_landing"><h3>Simple XML</h3></a>
		<p>Develop, integrate, and enhance apps in languages developers know and love</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/maps_landing"><h3>Splunk Maps</h3></a>
		<p>Use Simple XML to embed and manage native Splunk Maps to display results</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/framework_landing"><h3>Web Development</h3></a>
		<p>New Web Framework extends Splunk dashboards with client and server-side scripting</p>
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6ManagementImage" class="SplunkImageCell">
		<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/splunk6managementIcon.png" alt="Management" />
	</td>
	<td id="Splunk6Management" class="Splunk6HomeCell">
		<h1>Simplified Management</h1>
		<p>Simplified and scalable management capabilities for enterprise Splunk deployments</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/forwarder_landing"><h3>Forwarder Management</h3></a>
		<p>Easy-to-use interface for deployment server and managing forwarders</p>
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/cluster_landing"><h3>Simplified Cluster Management</h3></a>
		<p>Monitor cluster health and manage deployments through a new, centralized dashboard</p>
	</td>
   </tr>

  </table>
 </div>
</div>
		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
