<dashboard isVisible="false">
	<label>Predictive Analytics</label>
	<row>
        <html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/pivot_landing"><h2 align="left">Previous: Pivot</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/simple_dashboards_landing"><h2 align="right">Next: Simple XML</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
	</row>
	<row>
        <html>
		<p>Splunk enables you to use reports and dashboards to monitor activity as it is happening, then drill down into events and do a root-cause analysis. If there are patterns
		and correlations to events that you monitor, you can use them to predict future activity. With this knowledge, you can pro-actively send alerts based on thresholds and perform
		"what-if" analyses to compare various scenarios.</p>
		<p>Predictive Analytics commands are part of the search language.  Results are delivered in the same way as summary statistics with the option to visualize the results.  Predictive analytics can be used in a number of ways. For example:</p>
		<li>To help with capacity planning by letting you determine your hardware requirements for virtual environments and forecast energy consumption.</li>
		<li>It enables enhanced root cause analysis that can help detect abnormal patterns in events and prevent security attacks.</li>
		<li>It enables enhanced monitoring of key components which can detect system failures and prevent outages before they occur.</li>
            <h1>Using Predictive Analytic commands</h1>
            <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		<p>The Splunk search language includes two forecasting commands: <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0/SearchReference/Predict" target="_blank">Predict</a>
		and <a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0/SearchReference/x11" target="_blank">x11</a>.</p>
		<li>The Predict command enables you to use different forecasting algorithms to predict future values of single and multi-valued fields.</li>
		<li>The x11 command, which is named after the X11 algorithm, removes seasonal fluctuations in fields to expose the real trend in your underlying data series.</li><br/>
		<p>Constructing a search using predictive is straight forward, the following search string generates the predicted results in the chart on the right</p>
		<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/predictive_search.png" />
	    </div>
	    <h1>Example</h1>
	    <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		Dashboard with predictions of events.
		<a href="/app/splunk6overview/splunk6_predict" >Predict - Flight Cancellations</a>
	    </div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/predictive_results.png" />
		</div>
        </html>
	</row>
	<row>
		<html>
			<h1>Resources</h1>
			<a href="/help?location=whatsnew.predictiveanalytics" target="_blank"><h2>Learn More</h2></a>
			<a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0beta/ReleaseNotes/MeetSplunk" target="_blank"><h2>Intro to Splunk 6 documentation</h2></a>
		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
	
