<dashboard isVisible="false">
	<label>Simple Dashboards</label>
	<row>
        <html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/predictive_landing"><h2 align="left">Previous: Predictive Analytics</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<a href="/app/splunk6overview/maps_landing"><h2 align="right">Next: Splunk Maps</h2></a>
		</div>
	</html>
	</row>
        <row>
        <html>
		<p>Splunk’s Simple XML syntax allows any user to create and manage dashboards through the visual dashboard editor. Users can also manage privacy settings, modify searches, and
		manage panel controls for form inputs. The simple dashboard engine also no longer depends on the Advanced XML module system. Dashboards are now rendered in HTML and JavaScript,
		providing web developers with a more familiar interface for customizing their dashboards. </p>
		<h1>Key Features:</h1>
            <ul>
                <li>Improved Experience with Forms - Changing your simple xml dashboard to form now retains all the same edit controls (drag-and-drop panel, add/edit panel controls, and more)</li>
                <li>Enhanced Token Replacement - Form input tokens may now be used throughout your dashboard (panel titles, html panels, charting options, and more)</li>
                <li>Removed Panel per Row Limits - May now include more than 3 panels per row</li>
                <li>Cascading Form Inputs - Ability to use the selection of one form input to reduce/set the values of another form input</li>
	    </ul>
            <h1>Using the Simple dashboard</h1>
            <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		<p>Creating a dashboard is easily done from a search.  Start by creating a simple search as shown below:</p>
		<p><img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/simplexml_search.png" alt="search index=faa | stats count by DestState DestAirport | sort - count"/></p>
		<p>Once the search results are generated use the "Save as Dashboard" to create the dashboard.  Once the dashboard is created you can either add new search results or edit the
		underlying XML using the "Edit Source".</p>
		<p>There are many ways to customize and enhance your dashboards using simple XML</p>
		<ul>
			<li>One-click Add a time range picker</li>
			<li>Full range of charts</li>
			<li>Integrated Splunk <a href="/app/splunk6overview/maps_landing">Maps</a> support</li>
			<li>Customization extensions</li>
			<li>Form inputs</li>
		</ul>
	    </div>
	    <h1>Examples</h1>
	    <div STYLE="margin-left: 20px;">
		<p>The following dashboards are examples of the ways to customize a dashboard.  For a view of the underlying Simple XML you can edit the source code</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><a href="/app/splunk6overview/splunk6_dashboards_example">Cancelled Flights Analysis (simple)</a></li>
                        <li><a href="/app/splunk6overview/splunk6_dashboards_form_inputs">Airport Analysis (forms)</a></li>
                        <li><a href="/app/splunk6overview/splunk6_dashboards_maps">Cancelled Flights by Airport (maps)</a></li>
                    </ul>
            </div>
	</html>
	<html>
		<div>
			<img src="/static/app/splunk6overview/images/simplexml_forms.png" />
		</div>
        </html>
    </row>
	<row>
		<html>
			<h1>Resources</h1>
			<a href="http://localhost:8000/en-US/help?location=whatsnew.simplexmlediting"><h2>Learn More about</h2></a>
			<a href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.0beta/ReleaseNotes/MeetSplunk" target="_blank"><h2>Intro to Splunk 6 documentation</h2></a>
		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
	
