<dashboard>
  <label>Introduction</label>
  <description/>
  
  <row>
    <html>
      <h1>Welcome to the Extreme Networks EXOS app for Splunk<sup>®</sup>!</h1>
      <p>If this is your first time using this app, please follow <a href="/app/extreme_networks_basic/app_setup">this link to the app setup instructions</a> to properly configure your system to accept data.</p>
      <p><b>Purpose</b></p>
      <p>The purpose of this app is to help provide operational intelligence and insight into your Extreme Networks infrastructure. Our goal is to establish a framework with which you can easily monitor for potential issues occurring on your network.</p>
      <p><b>What can it do?</b></p>
      <p>Using this app, you will be able to, at a glance, see all of your Extreme Networks hardware, software, version information, and enabled features. You will also see information on the health of your network  -  important log messages, hardware warnings, and potential memory and CPU problem states.</p>
      <p><b>Why is this useful?</b></p>
      <p>With this information in hand, you will be able to quickly track down the source of network issues and see swifter resolution with the help of our Technical Assistance Center.</p>
      <p><b>Any other requirements?</b></p>
      <p>In order to receive the maximum benefit of this app, Extreme Networks devices need to be running EXOS v15.4 or higher with proactive tech support functionality enabled.</p>
	  <p><b>Future plans?</b></p>
      <p>This is an ongoing development project at Extreme Networks, with many planned enhancements, upgrades, and new features.</p>
      <p><b>Submitting feedback?</b></p>
      <p>If you have questions, comments, concerns, feature requests, or bug reports, please direct them to <a href="mailto:splunk@extremenetworks.com">splunk@extremenetworks.com</a>.</p>
      <br/>
      <p><b>Note:</b> for detailed instructions on how to configure your Extreme Networks devices to work with this app, look in the Documents menu on the navigation bar, under <b>EXOS Requirements and Configuration for Using the Splunk App</b></p>
      <br/>
      <p>All of the information contained in these dashboards is historic rather than real-time. The frequency at which you set the tech-support collector to push data to Splunk will impact how near to real-time the resulting dashboards are reliable.</p>
    
    </html>
    
  </row>
</dashboard>