<dashboard>
  <label>User Guide</label>
  <description />
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <body>
          <h1>Overview</h1>
          <p>This is a simple guide describing how you can use this Splunk app. Click the 'Editor' link in app menu to launch it.</p>
          
          <h1>Editor</h1>
          <img src="/static/app/mimosa/img/editor.png" width="480" />
          <p>
            <h2>Usage:</h2>
            <p>Simply enter SPL in the editor, the central part of the UI. If you don't know how to use Vim, just press 'i' to enter editing mode.</p>
            <h2>Features:</h2>
            <ul>
              <li>SPL Syntax Highlighting</li>
              <li>Multi line editing, you can split your SPL into multiple lines, with each line containing one or more SPL commands</li>
              <li>Vim binding, the editor uses Vim binding by default. If you are not familiar with Vim, just press 'i' to enter editing mode and use it as a plain editor. If you are a Vim user, thanks to CodeMirror, the <a class="external" href="http://codemirror.net/demo/vim.html">Vim binding in the editor</a> allows you to use lots of Vim features, which even includes full macro support.</li>
              <li>Use comment during editing, starting a line with `#`, the comment line will be safely ignored before submitting to Splunk enterprise</li>
              <li>Features accessible via keyboard shortcuts (Mac only):
                <ul>
                  <li>Quickly format SPL. If you copy/paste a long SPL into the editor, you can press 'Shift + Cmd + L' to ask the editor automatically format it into a multi line search string in the editor for ease of reading/editing</li>
                  <li>Look up search command usage. Press 'Shift + Cmd + D' to look up the search command in the current line, and its usage documentation will be displayed inline in the editor. You can toggle it on and off by pressing 'Shift + Cmd + D' again.</li>
                </ul>
              </li>
            </ul>
          </p>
          
          <h1>Pipeline visualizer</h1>
          <img src="/static/app/mimosa/img/pipeline.png" width="300" />
          <p>
            <h2>Usage:</h2>
            <p>The pipeline visualizer helps you to review an authored SPL more quickly.</p>
            <h2>Features:</h2>
            <ul>
              <li>Search command visualization. Nine most frequently used search commands, covering around 75% search command usage, have special visualizations, including:
                <ul>
                  <li>eval</li>
                  <li>fields</li>
                  <li>rename</li>
                  <li>search</li>
                  <li>sort</li>
                  <li>stats</li>
                  <li>table</li>
                  <li>timechart</li>
                  <li>top</li>
                </ul>
              </li>
              <li>Auto sync with the SPL in the editor</li>
            </ul>
          </p>
          
          <h1>Online shell</h1>
          <img src="/static/app/mimosa/img/seashell.png" width="480" />
          <p>
            <h2>Usage:</h2>
            <p>Click one of the rows in the search results in the bottom of the page, and enter `eval {somEvalExpression}` to run eval command against the selected row. Namely, if your eval command refers some field name, the selected row's coresspondingly field value will be used. And you can type 'help' command in the online shell for detailed usage on other commands. The eval expression syntax is the same as <a class="external" href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.2.3/Search/Usetheevalcommandandfunctions">Splunk eval command</a>, but you have to ignore the `{field_name}=`. For example, in SPL, you will use `eval pi_sum = 1 + pi()` but in the online shell, you can do `eval 1 + pi()`.</p>
            <h2>Features:</h2>
            <ul>
              <li>Instant eval expression evaluation. You don't need to submit a search to Splunk enterprise just to know if it has valid syntax. You can instead select a row in the search result, and develop your eval expression online and verify it against the search result you select.</li>
              <li>Evaluate search expression against a data record in search result to understand why it gets matched.</li>
            </ul>
          </p>
          
          <h1>Notes:</h1>
          <ul>
            <li>Since the SPL will be submitted to Splunk enterprise during your authoring, instead of running the search against a huge production data set, it is recommended to run it against a small data set for SPL development purpose. But don't worry too much since if the search job is still ongoing for a long running search, the editor will cancel the previously submitted search job before submitting a new one.</li>
            <li>There is not time picker in the UI currently, you have to use <a class="external" href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/6.2.3/SearchReference/SearchTimeModifiers">time modifier for search</a> in the editor to specify the time range manually.</li>
            <li>You can click the layout toggler (in the center of the layout resizer of a panel) to toggle a panel quickly.</li>
          </ul>
          
          <h1>References:</h1>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <a class="external" href="http://docs.splunk.com/Documentation/Splunk/latest/SearchReference/ListOfSearchCommands">Splunk search commands</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </body>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>
