<dashboard stylesheet="install.css">
	<label>Using the SplunkWeb Search Widget</label>
	<row>
		<html>
			<h1>Creating your first Splunk Search Dashboard</h1>

			<p>SCOM 2012 locates dashboards within management packs.  Our process to create a dashboard involves:</p>

			<ul>
				<li>Creating a management pack to hold the Splunk dashboards</li>
				<li>Creating a dashboard within the created management pack</li>
				<li>Adding the Splunk Search widget to the dashboard</li>
			</ul>

			<p>You can locate a dashboard within any management pack.  However, we recommend that you follow Microsoft 
			best practices and create a management pack for this purpose.</p>
		</html>
	</row>
	
	<row>
		<html>
			<h2>Creating a Management Pack to Contain the Dashboard View</h2>

			<p>SCOM best practices state that you create your own management packs to hold custom views.  This procedure will create an empty management pack.</p>

			<ul>
				<li>Start SCOM Operations Console as an Administrator</li>
				<li>Select the Administration Panel located in the left-hand sidebar.</li>
				<li>In the Administration tree, select the Management Packs item.</li>
				<li>In the Actions pane, click the "Create Management Pack" link.  This will open a wizard.
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/define_1.png"/></div>
				</li>
				<li>In the General Properties page of the wizard, give the management pack the name "Splunk Dashboards"</li>
				<li>Click Next to move to the Knowledge wizard page;</li>
				<li>Click Create to finalize the management pack.  The wizard will close automatically.
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/define_2.png" /></div>
				</li>
			</ul>
		</html>
	</row>
	
	<row>
		<html>
			<h2>Creating a Splunk Search Dashboard</h2>

			<ul>
				<li>Start SCOM Operations Console</li>
				<li>Select the Monitoring Panel located in the left-hand sidebar.</li>
				<li>In the Monitoring tree, find the Splunk Dashboards folder.  Right-click the folder node, and select New > Dashboard View
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_1.png" /></div>
				</li>
				<li>In the New Dashboard and Widget Wizard that appears, select the Column Layout and click Next</li>
				<li>In the General Properties page of the wizard, give the dashboard view the name "SplunkWeb Search"</li>
				<li>Click Next to move to the Column Count wizard page</li>
				<li>Click Next to approve a single-column layout</li>
				<li>Click Create to finalize the dashboard view.  Once the wizard has completed click Close.
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_2.png" /></div>
				</li>
			</ul> 

		</html>
	</row>

	<row>
		<html>
			<h2>Adding the Splunk Search widget to the SCOM Dashboard View</h2>
	
			<p>To add the SplunkWeb Search widget to a dashboard view:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Select the Monitoring Panel located in the left-hand sidebar.</li>
				<li>In the Monitoring tree, find the Splunk Dashboards folder and expand it.</li>
				<li>Click on the SplunkWeb Search dashboard.</li>
				<li>In the SplunWeb Search dashboard, click the link labeled "Click to add widget"
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_3.png" /></div>
				</li>
				<li>In the New Dashboard and Widget Wizard, expand the Splunk node and select the SplunkWeb Search widget
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_4.png" /></div>
				</li>
				<li>Give the widget a name and click Next.
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_5.png" /></div>
				</li>
				<li>In the SplunkWeb Configuration wizard page, enter the configuration details for the SplunkWeb host.  
				Be sure to specify the port used from SplunkWeb access (for example, port 8000 by default).  Enter 
				credentials for a user with authorization to use the SplunkWeb search app.
					<div class="step_image"><img src="/static/app/Splunk_on_SCOM/create_6.png" /></div>
				</li>
				<li>Click Next, then Create to add the widget to the dashboard view.  When the wizard is 
				complete, click the close button.</li>
			</ul>
			
			<p>Once the widget is added to a dashboard view, you will be able to use the SplunkWeb Search app in 
			that dashboard as if you had accessed the feature from a browser.</p>

			<a class="button_link" href="first_search">Next &gt;</a>
		</html>
	</row>   
</dashboard>
